我準備上學去
I'm getting ready for school.
把門打開 安德魯
[ Bangs ]Open this door, Andrew.
- 照我說的做- 不 你醉了
Listen to me.No, you're drunk.
我什麼?
I'm what?
再說一次?
Excuse me?
我叫你開門
I said unlock the door.
安德魯?
Andrew?
爸 現在才早上七點半 你已醉了
Dad, it is 7:30 in the a.m.,and you are drunk.
- 我醉不醉不是由你說的 你這小渾蛋- 你不是嗎?
Listen. You don't tell me if I'm drunkor not, you little shit. Aren't you?
你在裡面幹什麼?
What are you doing in there, huh?[ Bangs]
- 我把這錄下來了- 啊?
I'm filming this.Huh?
- 什麼?- 我買了個攝影機，從今以後我要把這些全錄下來
What? I bought a camera, and I'mfilming everything from here on out.
現在只需花46.5美元你就能擁有它，沒錯！
[ Woman On TV] And itis yoursright now for only 46.50! Yeah!
媽 媽
[Andrew]Mom? Mom.
嘿
[ Murmurs]Hey.
跟我的新攝影機打聲招呼
Say helloto my new camera for me.
- 觀眾是誰?- 只是在家裡觀看視頻的幾百萬人而已
Who's the audience? Just the millionsof people that are watching at home.
- 我看起來很糟嗎?- 不 不 媽
Do I look awful?No, no, no, Mom.
你...你看起來好極了
You look-You look great.
- 是個不錯的攝影機- 謝了 媽
It's a nice camera.[Chuckles] Well, thanks, Mom.
那麼 我該問問這攝影機是怎麼回事嗎...
So, um, should I askabout the camera or-
不 我只是...我要開始記錄東西了
[Andrew] Uh, I don't know.I'm- I'm filming things now.
- 我要把一切都錄下來- 你什麼都錄?
I'm filming everything.You're filming everything?
- 是的- 好吧
Yeah.Okay.
為什麼人人對此著迷？
（Jessie J - Price Tag）
J Why is everyone so obsessed? J
滿足與快樂 金錢無法買到
,P Money can't buy us happiness ,PWow.
讓我們放慢腳步 活在當下
; We should all slow downand enjoy right now ,P
人人向左看看
J Look to their left ;
人人向右看看
; Everybody look to their right ;
天啊 別唱了吧
God, make it stop.
不是關於金錢 金錢
J Cha-ching, cha-ching ;
也不是關於穿金戴銀
[ Chuckles ]J Ain't about the- yeah- ba-bling, ba-bling ;
只想讓世人共舞
; Want to make the world dance J
共同忘掉身價牌
; Forget about the price tag ,VJ
你有沒有讀過亞瑟 叔本華?
Have you ever readany Arthur Schopenhauer?
沒有 誰是亞瑟 叔本華?
[Andrew ]No. What is Arthur Schopenhauer?
他是個哲學家 我現在正在讀他的作品
He's, um- He's this philosopherthat I'm reading at the moment.
- 是學校作業?- 不是
For school?No, no.
基本上 人類需要意識到...
Uh, basically, human beingshave to recognize themselves...
- 自己是充滿純意志的個體 懂嗎?- 是的
as beings of pure will, right?Okay.
這表示所有感情上與肉體上的欲望都永遠不能被滿足
So all emotional and physical desirescan never be fulfilled.
你是說我們乾脆都不要活下去了
So basically you're telling methat I should give up on life.
- 是的- 好吧
Yes. [ Chuckles ] Okay.
快點啊，大哥！天啊
[Student] Come on, man![Andrew] Oh, God.
待會見好的，哥們，再見
I'll see you later.[Student #21 All right, dude. Peace.
學習時間到了
Learning time.
讓路啊
Get out of the way.
你不走嗎?我再待一會 好嗎?
[Andrew] Are you not coming in?I'm gonna hang back a while, okay?
第一節課你會遲到的
Uh, you're gonna be latefor first period.
-第七節後我會去接你
Yeah. I'll pick you up after seventh.JJ [Rock]
這是我的學校
[ Chattering ] [Andrew] This is my school.
算是吧
I guess.
好的
[ Shouts, Laughs][Andrew ] Okay.
嘿 你 就是你 高年級生班導選舉 投票給史蒂夫
Hey, you! Hey, guy.Vote for Steve for senior class president.
- 投給史蒂夫- 好 我知道了
Vote for Steve.Yeah, I got it.
這是我吃午餐的地方
[Andrew ]This is where I eat lunch.
在看臺上
[Whistle Blows]Out here on the bleachers.
。。。4,5,6,7,8。再來，1。。。
...Four, five, six, seven, eight.And one-
我不想看到有人停下，對了
[ Male Coach ] 'Cause I don't wannasee anybody pull up- That's right.
移到左邊，就這樣，傑克，對了，好的
Way to your left. There you go, Jack.That's right. Okay.
一支團結的隊伍
[ Bag Rustling]A cohesive unit today.
。。。勝利！勝利！
[Chips Crunching]...O-R-Y! V-I-C-T-O-R-Y!
我不想看到偷懶，好嗎？
I don't want to seeany crap out there. All right?
勝利！
[All 1...T-o-R-Y!
哇哦！做得好，好的
Whoo! [ Coach ] Good job.All right.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
[Andrew ]Hey.
你可以不要拍我們嗎? 這挺詭異的
Could you not videotape us, please?It's really creepy.
不 我不是在...
Uh, no. I wasn't-
我的儲物櫃就在這走廊
Hi! This is the hallwaywhere my locker is.
這是怎麼回事?
[ Groans ]What is this?
怎樣 戴特摩?
What's up, Detmer?[All Chattering ]
- 哇 你應該上電視- 老兄 你在拍電影啊
Wow, you should be on television.Man, you're on a film, man.
還挺上鏡的嘛
Pretty on camera.
- 笑一個 夥計 你很上鏡- 你要哭了嗎? 要哭了嗎?
Smile, man. You look pretty.You gonna cry? You gonna cry?
蕭恩 快還給我
[ Bell Rings ] [Andrew] Sean, come on.Give it back.
你要你的攝影機嗎? 什麼2004年的破爛啊
Huh? You want your camera?Piece of shit from, like, 2004?
給你吧 來 完好如初
Here you go. Here she is.In one piece.
別這樣
- Oh! - [Andrew] Oh, guys.
差不多吧
[ Sean ] Almost.[Chuckles] [Andrew Groans]
混蛋們！過來！
[Andrew ] Assholes! Come on!
好的，你們準備好“大幹一場”了嗎？
All right.You ready to bounce? Yeah.
今晚有個派對
There's a party tonight.
好的
Okay.
黑文丘
Haven Hills.
黑文丘不是關了嗎?
[Andrew] Wait.I thought Haven Hills was closed.
現在是報廢的 是啊 你不想去嗎?
It's abandoned, yeah.What, you don't want to go?
不想
No.
- 你上回去派對是什麼時候?- 我從不去派對
When was the last time you went to a party?I don't go to parties.
- 你是個高年級生- 我不去派對
You're a senior. You are a senior.I don't go to parties.
- 來就對了- 我考慮考慮 好嗎?
Just come.I'll think about it, okay?
好吧
Okay.
如果你真要去 安德魯我給你一個專家的建議
But when we go tonight, Andrew,can I give you, like, a pro tip?
什麼?
What?
把攝影機留在家裡
Maybe leave your camera at home.
- 為什麼?- 因為有點怪
Why?Because it's a little weird.
這是有用處的
It serves a purpose.
我...我只是想當個好表兄 好嗎?
I'm- I'm just trying to bea good cousin here, okay?
做為你的朋友 我告訴你...
This is me being your friendand telling you...
你最好不要帶個攝影機去參加派對
you should probablynot take the camera to a party.
好吧
[Andrew ]Okay.
這是我住的街
This is my street.
那些是我們街上的頭號混帳
And those are the officialdouche bags of my street.
- 那他媽的是什麼?- 太好了
What the hell's that?Oh, great.
喂 你在幹什麼 安德魯
Hey! What you doing?Andrew!
- 不 我沒有...- 別拍我 戴特摩 別拍我
No, I wasn't- Don't film me, Detmer!Don't film me.
趕快跑回家吧 賤人
Run to your house, bitch![Glass Breaking ]
這是我吃午餐的地方
This is where I eat lunch.
在看臺上
Out here on the bleachers.
你想怎樣?
What do you want?[ Groans ]
我叫你開門 你就開門 懂嗎?
When I say open that door, youopen the door. You got it?
把你該死的作業寫完
Finish your goddamn homework.
- 麥特 你確定在這裡嗎?- 夥計 在這裡 放鬆點 好嗎?
[Andrew] Matt, are you sure it's here?Dude, it's here. Calm down, okay?
就是這
Oh, here it is.,U [ Electronic Dance ]
喔 太好了
[Crowd Chattering ][Andrew ] Oh, yeah.
哇 看這狂歡
Wow. Look. A rave.
哇 看這拿個攝影機的書呆子
[ Matt] Oh, wow. Look.A nerd with a camera.
別一整晚都跟著我 好嗎?
[Andrew] What? Just don't followme around all night, okay?
你什麼意思 我以為...你不是要我跟你一起來的嗎?
What do you mean? I thought- I thoughtyou wanted me to come with you.
是啊 但就這一次 你自己去找點樂子吧
I did. I did. But just go and doyour own thing for once, okay?
去喝杯酒 跟別人聊聊天
Just... have a beer, talk to people.JJ [ Continues ]
我不喝酒
[Andrew]I don't drink.
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
嘿
[Woman ]Hey!
借過 嘿 你在拍什麼?
Excuse me.Hey! Hey, what are you filming for?
我不是...呃
Oh, I don't- Um-
什麼?
Uh-What?
- 我聽不到- 我只是隨便拍拍
- I can't hear you.- I'm just filming.
酷喔 我是為了我的博客拍的
- Oh. Oh, cool. Cool. I'm filming for my blog.- Oh.
- 安德魯- 你應該看看 它其實...
Andrew. Andrew. You should check it out.It's actually-
- 嘿 凱西- 嘿
Oh, hey. Hey, Casey.Hey.
- 你好嗎?- 我很好 很好
How you doing?I'm good. I'm good.
這挺沒勁的 對吧?
This is pretty lame, right?
怎麼沒勁?
Why is it lame?
你也知道 卡爾 榮格說過...
You know, Jung saidparties are just...
派對只是人們找尋大眾的肯定的方法
people's way ofseeking widespread validation.
我不是那種需要耍酷的 懂嗎
I'm not one to clamorto be cool, you know.
哇 用心理學來分析一個農場派對還真厲害呀 麥特
Wow. Way to put an analytical psychologyspin on this barn party, Matt.
真了不起
That's awesome.
了不起
Awesome.
- 你才了不起- 喂 麥特
You're awesome.[ Andrew ] Hey, Matt.
榮格對螢光棒有什麼看法?
Hey, what did Jung say about glow sticks?[Chuckles]
你在拍我女朋友嗎?
JJ [ Electronic Dance]
有還是沒有?
You filming my girlfriend?
不 我...我什麼都沒拍
Yes or no?
我只是在拍派對
No, I- I'm not filming anything.I'm just filming the party. Okay.
我應該把你的賤鼻子打斷 知道嗎?
I should break your bitch-ass nose.You know that?
- 不 我沒有...- 別跟我回嘴
No, I wasn't-Don't talk back to me.
- 賤人- 好的
Bitch.Okay.
安德魯?
[ Male Student]Andrew?
安德魯
Andrew.
拿攝影機的那人
With the camera.
- 可以...可以借我們用用嗎?- 什麼?
Can we- Can we use that thing?What?
我們發現了超正的玩意一定得錄下來
We found the craziest shit,and we gotta get it on tape.
- 這...這不是...- 你還好嗎 老兄?
Uh, it's not-What's up, man?
- 你沒事吧?- 是的 我是安德魯
You okay?Yeah. I'm-I'm Andrew.
我是史蒂夫
Okay. I'm Steve.
- 史蒂夫 蒙特高梅利- 是的 我知道
Steve Montgomery.Yeah, I know.
是嗎?
Really?
麥特和我隨便混混...
Matt and I were just hanging out,
我們找到一個很酷的一個...
and we found this cool little-
- 一個東西- 等等 你跟麥特在一起?
this thing.Wait. You're with Matt?
- 你會想把它錄下來- 不 我只是...我真的不想...
You might want to get it on tape.No, I just- I don't really-
夥計 來嘛 來錄下來吧 很酷的
Dude, just come on.Just come get it on tape. It'll be cool.
- 我不確定- 相信我
I don't know.Trust me.
- 好吧- 好傢伙
All right.Yeah, man.
你也知道這裡有一堆女孩吧?
You know there are, like,tons of girls around here, right?
你卻自己一個人 站在一棵樹旁?
And you're all by yourselfnext to a tree?
我很挑剔
I'm just really picky.
- 聽好 我真的不想...- 你那玩意上有燈嗎?
Listen. I really don't think- ls there alight on that thing? Like, on the camera?
有啊 在這
Uh, yeah. Here.
你們跑到這來幹什麼?
What were you guysdoing out here?
原先來了一群人因為大家都被那東西迷上了
A bunch of people were out here 'causewe were, like, obsessed with the thing.
到底什麼東西?
What thing?
看就知道
You'll see.
喔 對了 沒錯 你是安德魯 戴特摩
Oh, that's- that's right!Andrew Detmer!
高一主教室時 我記得你
I remember you from homeroom,freshman year.
你總是穿著那件灰色的連帽外套
You always had thatgray zip-up hoodie.
- 加雷蒂!- 你還記得那些?
Garetty!You remember that?
是啊 我對記臉孔很有一套所以我才要搞政治
Yeah, I got a- I got a thing for faces,which is why I'm going into politics.
挺諷刺的 因為我實在...
Ironically enough,'cause I'm so ridiculously hi-
- 在這- 啊 來吧
[ Matt] Down here!Ah, there we go.
- 加雷蒂 如何? 我看到你了- 麥特
Garetty, what's up?I see you! Matt!
- 你看到我了嗎?- 是的 其他人都跑哪了?
[ Matt] You see me?Yeah, where did everybody go?
都走了 都走了 來吧 快快快
They left! They left! Come on.Let's go, let's go, let's go!
- 你看到了嗎?- 夥計們 那是什麼?
[ Steve ] Do you see that?Guys, what is that?
- 你看到了嗎? 那是攝影機嗎?- 是啊 我找到他了
Do you see it? Is that the camera?Yeah, I got him!
- 你們知道回去的路嗎?- 它還在發出那聲響嗎?
Do you guys know how to get back from here?Is it still making that sound?
- 對 你告訴安德魯了嗎?- 安德魯 那聲音是它發出的
Yes. Did you tell Andrew?Andrew, it's making that sound, dude.
夥計 過來聽聽看 聽聽
Dude, come and listen to this.Listen to this.
- 不不不 你得靠近些- 好啦 好啦
No, no, no, no.You gotta get in. Okay, okay.
你得靠很近 幾乎快進洞裡了好的，別推我，別推我下去啊
You gotta get close, like literally almost in the hole.Okay, don't push me. Just don't push me.
- 聽聽這玩意- 我們不會推你的。我們只想把它拍下來
Check this shit out. We're not gonna push you in.We're just trying to get it on camera.
聽著 你聽到嗎?噓，噓
Listen. Can you hear that?Shh, shh.
什麼...
What-[ Loud Rumble]
應該錄下來了
[ Laughing ]I think we got it.
等等 這太詭異了
Wait. How creepy is that?
- 你收得到這聲音嗎?- 我不知道 應該吧 挺大聲的
Is this sound coming up? I don't know.I mean, probably. It's pretty loud, right?
好了 夥計 我們進去吧
[ Matt 1 Hello! All right, dude.We're going inside.
- 我要回去了 快啦- 我要知道...
I'm going back. Come on, you guys.I gotta know.
- 麥特 說真的 我們...- 等等 史蒂夫
[Andrew ] Matt, seriously,we- Hey, wait, wait. Steve!
史蒂夫
[ Shouts ]Steve!
操 他活像個忍者
[ Matt Chuckles ]Oh, shit! He's a ninja.
麥特...
Matt-
麥特 麥特 你要去哪?
Whoa, Matt, Matt, Matt.What are you doing?
你是認真的嗎?
Are you serious?
- 安德魯 可以給我照點光嗎?- 麥特 別傻了
Andrew, can you give me some light?Matt, don't be an idiot.
哇哦！哇哦！
Whoop! Whoop!
麥特 我靠你回家耶
Matt!Matt, you're my ride home!
哈嘍？
[Andrew ] Hello? [ Coughing ]
噢！
Oh![ Groans ]
這裡面好臭
Smells terrible.You guys!
麥特
Matt!
哈嘍？
Hello?[ Shouts ]
- 安德魯是個膽小鬼- 好啦 這隧道很深嗎?
Andrew's such a pussy. All right.Does it go down much deeper, or what?
- 是啊 夥計 深得很- 安德魯 照點光
Yeah, man. It goes really, really far.[ Matt] Andrew, bring the light.
看那石壁 整個是垂直的
Look at the walls.It's like a straight shot down.
我們說不定已走了四十到五十英尺
Probably already comelike 40 or 50 feet.
別講了 好嗎?
[Andrew ] Yeah, just don'ttalk about it, okay?
你沒讀過柏拉圖的"地穴寓言"嗎?
You ever- You ever heard of Plato's “Allegory of the Cave”?
沒有 麥特 我們快點了結這事吧
I don't know, Matt.Let's just get this over with.
媽的
Oh, Shit!
天啊
Holy shit.
那他媽的是什麼?
The hell is that?
麥特 我不是在開玩笑 我呼吸不了
[Low Humming] [Andrew] Matt, I'm not kidding.I can't breathe.
安德魯 看看這個
Come on.Andrew, look at this.
什麼...
[ Andrew ]What-
你能相信嗎?
Can you believe this?
麥特
[ Andrew ]Matt.
這是什麼?
[Andrew] What am I looking at?[ High-pitched Screech ]
- 媽的- 我怕的要死
Ah, shit! [Andrew ] I amfreaking out right now!
麥特 拜託我們出去吧?
Matt!Can we get out of here, please?
這攝影機拍得到嗎?
Is it showing upon the camera like that?
我不知道
[ High-pitched Screeching ] I don't know, man.it's messing with it. I don't really want to film-
它干擾到了攝影機 我不想拍...
[ Matt, Distorted]Dude, I'll buy you a new one.
夥計 我給你買個新的
[Low Humming]
摸摸看
[ Steve, Distorted ]Touch one.
麥特
Matt!
- 麥特 來看啊- 什麼?
Matt, look at this!What?
看看這個
Look at this!
夥計 這是...
Dude, what is-
夥計 不會吧
Dude, no way!
- 它在變色- 我的天啊
It's changing colors!Oh, my God.
應該是對溫度產生反應
[ Distorted Screeching ] [Distorted] Must be reacting to heat.
- 我聽不到你...- 這太正了
- [Andrew] I can't hear you over that-- This is awesome.
夥計 你的鼻子
Oh! Dude, your nose!
史蒂夫，史蒂夫！
[ Distorted Thumping ]Steve, Steve!
史蒂夫
[ Distorted Rumbling ]Steve!
- Steve!- [Steve Screaming ]
麥特 把手機放下 關掉
[Andrew] Matt, dude, put your phone down.Turn it off.
- 好啦 好啦- 史蒂夫 你也是
Okay, okay, okay.Steve, you too.
- 好的- 我們要把這紀錄下來
[Steve] All right.We have to document this.
- 好的 你們準備好了嗎?- 我好了
Okay. Are you guys ready?[Steve] Yeah. I'm ready.
- 好 開始吧 史蒂夫...- 怎樣?
All right. Here we go.Okay, Steve- What?
你可以往左站一點嗎?
Can you move to your left?
- 這裡?- 對 很好
Here?Um, yeah. That's good.
然後 麥特...
And then, Matt,
你可以站到史蒂夫前面嗎?
can you just goright in front of Steve?
額。。。
Um-
- 這裡?- 對 剛好 好的
Here? Yeah, perfect.Yeah, yeah. Okay.
這是球體試驗
This is the ball test.
- 準備好了嗎?- 好了
You ready?Yep.
噢！
Oh![ Laughing ]
搞屁啊 史蒂夫?
What the shit, Steve?[Andrew Laughing ]
滾開 滾開 你在幹什麼?叫你由下往上投的
Get off! Get off!What are you doing? Underhand.
我盡力了 老兄
I tried, man. I tried.[Groaning ]
- 來 再來一次- 好吧
Let's do it. Let's do it.All right.
- 好的 等等- 可以嗎?
All right. Wait, wait.We good?
- 說好由下往上投吧?- 是啊 由下往上
We said underhand, right?Yeah, it is underhand. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我看好你了 你這次不會打到我了
Underneath. I'm on you.You're not gonna get me this time.
- 準備好了嗎?- 好了
You ready? [ Andrew ] Yeah.
- 看准了- 我不知道你在說什麼
I'm on it. Yeah.I don't know what you're talking about.
來吧
Let's go.
喔！
Oh![Andrew Laughing ]
好耶 球迷歡聲雷動
Yeah!The crowd goes wild!
- 好 我準備好了- 麥特 給他個狠的
Yeah, I'm ready. [ Steve ] All right.Matt, beam him. Beam him.
- 我會的- 狠狠的
I'm- I'm going to.Beam him.
哦！
Oh!
不可能 操
Oh!No way! Shit!
等等 這太棒了
[ Laughing ] Wait, wait, wait.That's great!
- 他做到了- 我做到了 我做到了
He did it!I did it! I did it!
- 這太瘋狂了- 我的天啊
[ Steve] That is crazy!Oh, my God!
- 看那球- 我的天
Look at it!Oh, my God!
- 媽的- 我的天
[ Steve ] Holy shit! Oh, my God.
我的天 喔 夥計 你流血了
Oh, my God. Oh, dude, you're bleeding.You're bleeding.
- 停止 停止- 去拿張紙吧
[ Steve ] Oh, man, shit.Stop, stop, stop. Get a tissue.
你成功了！是的！
You did it! Yes![Steve Laughing]
哦，好的，高飛球，準備好了？好的
Oh. All right. Pop-up.Ready? Yeah.
好的！
[ Groans ]Yes!
放音樂。喔，耶
Put on the music.Oh, yeah.
好
[ Chuckles ] Yes.JJ [Dramatic /nstrumenta/]
Yes.
麥特 你必須想像你用手把它們捏在一起
Matt, you have- you have to pretend like you'resqueezing them together with your hands.
我就是這麼做啊 看
That's what I'm doing.Look. That's what I'm doing.
我做不到 夥計 我放棄
I can't do it, dude.[Groans] I give up.
你來 你比我會弄這個
You do it.You're better at this than I am.
真的嗎 我嗎?
Oh, really? Am I?Really?
弄就對了
Just do it.
噢
Oh.
正
[ Chuckles ]Sick.
夥計 我恨你 這...
Dude, I hate you!That's-
- 我佩服 老兄 我佩服- 這太驚人了
I'm impressed, man.I am impressed. That's amazing.
太了不起了 夥計
That was awesome, dude.
- 別這樣- 夥計
Oh, no!Come on, dude.
- 太沒風度了- 怎樣?
That is not cool.What?
- 沒風度- 是我的樂高
That is not cool.My Legos.
這三周你一直跟那兩個傢伙混
[ Woman ] You've been hanging out withthose two guys for the last three weeks.
- "三周"- 我並不蠢
鈥淭hree weeks.鈥?I'm not stupid
你在對我隱瞞著什麼 你最好回我電話
I think you're hiding something from me.You better call me back.
- 哇- 我愛你
[ Mad] Wow. I love you.
她會用磚頭砸我窗戶 我是真怕了
I'm gonna get a brick through my window.I am legitimately scared.
我馬上要競選了 沒時間搞這個
I have an election coming up,and I don't have time for this.
夥計 你為啥向我們要感情的建議?
Dude, why are you asking usfor advice on girls?
因為我們是他的情婦
Because we're his mistress.
那麼你認為是輻射之類的嗎?
[Andrew] So, what, you think it's,like, radiation or something?
- 哪來的輻射?- 夥計 都是政府啦
[Steve] Radiation from what?[ Matt] Dude, it's the government.
麥特 你在說什麼?
[Andrew] What?Matt, what are you talking about?
我其實已經冒夠了險
[Andrew ] I'm feeling prettyspelunked out actually.
安德魯 放心
[ Matt]Andrew, relax.
好奇怪啊 在白天看起來完全不一樣
[ Matt] That's so weird.It looks completely different during the day.
聽著 我不管 好嗎我不會再進那洞穴了
[Andrew] Look. I don't care, okay?I am not going in the hole again.
混蛋
[ Chuckling ]Asshole.
好像往裡面塌了還是什麼
[ Matt]It's like sunk in or something.
- 你的老攝影機也埋了- 媽的
[Steve Chuckles] There goes your oldcamera, dude. [Andrew] Oh, shit.
真奇怪 我還是能感覺到它的存在
[ Steve ] That's weird.I can still feel it down there.
我真無法相信我們活著出來
[ Andrew ] I can't believewe made it out of there.
那麼 我是說 這就算完了 對吧?
Well, I mean, that answers that, right?
什麼完了? 我們還是不知道發生了什麼事
[Andrew ] Um, what does?We still don't know what happened.
- 不...- 但我們還活著
No- [ Matt] Well,we're still alive.
- 我是說 我絕對...- 喂
I mean, I was definitely- [Helicopter Overhead ] [ Man ] Hey!
你們不能待在那 懂嗎?
You kids can't be here, okay?You gotta move on out. What?
- 你們必須離開- 什麼?
[ Helicopter Whirring ] The ground's unstable.We're taping the whole place off.
地基不穩定 我們要把整個空地封鎖
[ Chatter On Walkie-talkie ]
好的 我們走了
Okay. We're going.
投票給史蒂夫
[ Steve ] Vote for Steve![ Chuckles ]
新攝影機用得不錯 很好是啊 還挺酷的吧?
[ Steve ] New camera's working out for you.That's good. [Andrew] Yeah, it's pretty cool, right?
是啊 小型的 那錄到錄影帶上嗎?
Yeah, smaller.Does that shoot on tape?
不 直接存在攝影機裡吧
No, it just- It, like,records right onto the camera.
我只是想把我們的能力全紀錄下來
No, I just want to record all thestuff that we can do, you know.
好 但你隨時隨地都在拍
Yeah, but it's like all the time.
你不覺得這有一點怪嗎...
You don't feel likeit's a little weird,
就好像你和其他事物隔了一層障礙嗎?
like it puts a barrier betweenyou and everything else?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
或許我想要有一層障礙
Maybe I want a barrier.
那麼你老爸是怎麼回事?他的背景事業是什麼?
So, like, what's up with your dad?What's his story? What does he do?
呃 我爸是救火員
Um, my dad's a firefighter.
- 那很酷啊 一定挺了不起的...- 是啊 我是說 他曾經是
Okay. That's cool. Oh, man, that must havebeen awesome- Yeah, well, he was, I guess.
- 發生了什麼事?- 我也不知道 他沒死
What happened? Uh, I don't know.He didn't die or anything.
他只是...在火場受了傷
He just- He got injured onthe job, and now he, um-
現在他領那保險金 你知道
he collects the insurance,you know.
所以他啥都不幹
Um, so he doesn'treally do anything.
他救是...白天他會出門但我也不知道他去哪裡
He just- He, um- He'll go out during theday, but I don't know where he goes.
他喝很多酒
Uh, he drinks a lot.
這點我知道
I know that much.
我其實也跟我父母有點矛盾
I've actually been havingsome problems with my parents too.
是嗎？
Oh, yeah?
是啊，我是說他們跟你父母一點都不一樣
Yeah. I mean,they're nothing like yours.
我是說不像那樣。。。我只是。。。算了
I mean, not like that-I just- Never mind.
他們最近老吵架
They just been fighting a lot lately.
我覺得老媽背著老爸在外面瞎搞
And I think my momis actually cheating on my dad.
你就不能說點什麼嗎？
[ Steve ] Can you not sayanything about that?
是啊，沒門，謝了
[Andrew ] Yeah. No way. Thanks.
是的 凱倫 戴特摩
[ Father] Yes. Karen Detmer.D-E-T-M-E-R.
是的 謝謝你
Yes. Thank you.
她很痛苦
She's in pain.
她需要更強的藥
She needs something stronger.
她的呼吸惡化了
Her breathing's worse.
先生 她很痛苦
Sir, she's suffering.
請幫幫我
Please help me.
我是靠殘疾輔助金的 我付不起$700
I'm on disability.I can't afford $700.
請別讓我等 她不能呼吸 好嗎?我不知該怎麼做了
Please, don't put me on hold! She can't breathe, okay?I don't know what to do any more.
開了嗎?
Is it on?
是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah. You got it.
我想要記得這樣的你
I want to remember you like this.
媽
Oh, Mom.
你比這更堅強
You're stronger than this.
你可以為我說出來嗎?
Can you say that for me?
拜託?
Please?
我比這更堅強
I'm stronger than this.
喔 不錯
Oh, nice.
好了 看清楚
All right. Here. Watch this.
- 爛- 嘿 麥特
Weak.Hey, Matt.
怎樣?
Yeah?
你喜歡我嗎?
Do you like me?
是啊 當然
Um, yeah, of course.
我是說 你也知道 我不是...
I mean, you know,I didn't-
- 我不是一直喜歡你的- 什麼意思?
I mean, you know, I didn't always.What do you mean?
我不知道 你...
I don't know.Like, you haven't-
你不是那麼容易相處的 你知道...
You haven't always beensuper-easy to talk to, you know.
我不是說你現在不一樣了 只是...
I mean, I'm not saying thatyou're not now. I'm just-
你真是個混蛋
[ Scoffs ]You're such an asshole.
我就是這個意思 你不友善 懂嗎?
That's what I'm talking about, dude.You're hostile, see?
好多了
[Andrew Chuckling ]Better.
- 嘿 麥特- 怎樣?
Hey, Matt.Yeah?
你有沒有想過用這...
Do you ever think about, like,
做其他的事?
doing more with it?
用這能力嗎?
What, with this?
沒怎麼想過
Not really.
怎麼? 還有什麼能做的?
Why? What else is there?
- "隔空移物"- 是的 請指教
“Telekinesis.”  Yes.Do tell.
"能夠移動 抬起 震動"...
鈥淭he ability to move, lift, vibrate鈥?
震動是我最喜歡的
[Andrew Chuckles]That's my favorite.
"旋轉 扭曲 破碎 或碰撞物體的能力"
鈥淪pin, bend, breakor impact objects...
"透過念力的影響 或其他非碰觸的方法
through the direct influence of mentalpower or other nonphysical means.鈥?
- 好- 聽起來很熟悉
Okay.Sounds familiar.
- 聽起來是很熟悉- 非常熟悉
It does sound familiar.Very familiar.
你想見識念力的影響?
You want to see direct influence?
安德魯
[ Matt ] Andrew. [Whistles ]
她今天穿黑的
[All Laughing] [ Steve ]She's wearing black today.
這才是念力的影響
Hi.That's direct influence.
- ...在我房間裡- 聽著
...Week, in my room.Just listen.
我變得越來越強 昨晚我甚至把床抬了起來
I'm just that much stronger.Even last night I got my whole bed off the ground.
- 沒流鼻血- 是嗎? 我也有在舉重
No nosebleed. Yeah?I've been lifting weights too.
我的理論是 這能力像是條肌肉
This is my theory thoughis that it's like a muscle.
它有伸縮性如果一次張得太多太快 它會斷
Like, it's elastic. If you stretchit too far, too quick, it'll tear.
額
Ew.
這就是為什麼我們漸漸變強...
That's why I think we'regetting stronger, you know,
因為我們在訓練它 變得更壯
because we're working it out,getting buff.
更壯
Buff.[ Chuckles ]
這個當訓練怎麼樣?
How about this for a workout?
媽的
[ Laughs ]Holy shit!
那太正了
That was awesome.
真有禮貌
[ Burps ]Classy.
是啊 有魅力
Mm-hmm.Attractive.
我認為我們該闖闖後院以外了
I think it's time we took thisout of the backyard.
停停停 就在這 這裡剛好
[ Matt Chuckles] [Steve] Stop, stop, stop, stop.Right here. This is perfect.
- 真的嗎?- 就是這
[ Andrew ] Really? This is it.
麥特
Matt. Yah!
來整這個
[ Giggling ]Let's get this one.
喔！嘿！哈嘍！
Whoa! Hey! Hello!
- 怎麼搞的...- 安德魯
Hey, what- [ Matt ] Andrew.
請幫我攔住
Help! Somebody grab that!
喔！喔！打住！
[ Giggling]Whoa! Whoa! Stop!
- 好 我弄上面的- 知道了
[Andrew] Okay, I'll get the top.I'll get the top. [ Matt] Got it. Got it.
- 我們弄腿- 好 等等
[ Steve ] Let's get the legs.[ Matt] Okay. Wait.
"我在飛翔"
[ Steve Growling ]I'm flying!
她就盯著看
She's just looking at it.[ Screaming ]
你看什麼 小女孩? 別翹課啊
What you looking at, girl?Stay in school!
看到那個嚼口香糖的傢伙嗎?我要從他嘴里拉出口香糖
Okay, see the guy chewing the gum?I'm gonna get the gum and pull it right out of his mouth.
好 我拍著呢
[Andrew ]Okay, I got him.
哦！
Oh!
等一下 等等 我們跑什麼?我們不用跑啊
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Why are we running?We don't need to run.
- 五...- 我不想幹
[ Steve ] Five- Idon't want to do it.
- 四...- 夥計 我不想幹
Four-Dude, I don't want to do it.
- 你太招人耳目了 我不想幹- 來嘛 麥特
You're creating a scene. I don't want to do it.Come on, Matt. Don't be a bitch about it.
- 別耍孬 快- 把手放桌上就好了
Just do it.Put your hand on the table.
- 好你準備好了嗎?- 給我一個倒數
Okay. Are you ready? Do it.Give me a countdown.
我會 我發誓...
I will. I promi-OW!
被耍了
[ Laughing ]Oh, snap!
- 就像我說的...- 你得賠人家錢
Like I said- [ Steve ] Yougotta pay for that now.
就像我說的 看吧媽呀
Like I said. See?Holy crap.
就想像你手上方有個屏障 然後...
[ Steve] Man! Just pretend that there's abarrier over your hand, right? And then-
有物體要碰到你時 只要你準備好...
[ Steve] Mm-hmm. When things are gonnahit you, as long as you're ready,
- 你就有屏障保護 不會受到傷害- 這太正了
they will not hurt you because of the barrier.[ Matt] That's so sick.
那個我喜歡史蒂夫，史蒂夫，你得試試這個
[Steve] That's me right there. I need that.Steve, Steve, you have to try this, dude.
把手給我
Give me your hand.
當我還是小孩子的時候，我其實。。。其實想當一名員警
When I was a kid though, I actually- Iactually did want to be a police officer.
-員警？沒開玩笑吧
-是啊，是啊[ Steve ] A cop?No shit? Yeah. Yeah.
你知道當員警就不能抽大麻了，對吧，麥特？
You do know that you can't smokeweed when you're a cop, right, Matt?
哦，不，真的？額，我不知道
Oh, no. Really?Uh, I didn't know.
額，但是，不，我只是，我有些利他主義
Uh, but, no, I-I-I just-I really got into, like, altruism.
什麼意思？利他主義是什麼，麥特？
What does that mean? What does “altruism” mean, Matt?
就是為了別人讓世界變得美好
It's like wanting to make thingsbetter for everyone.
真的？這話居然從一個整天抱怨生活無意義的人口中說出來
Really? This coming from the man who isalways talking about how pointless life is.
是啊，我知道，但這就是我最近在思考的
Yeah, I know, but this is whatI've been thinking about lately.
就好像，我在回想，我只是覺得。。。
Like, I'm looking back,and I just think...
我以前看事情的角度可能更好，你知道嗎
the way I used to think about thingswas probably a lot better, you know.
那又如何，你要出去開始做慈善什麼的嗎？
So, what, you want to go out andstart a charity or something?
-這不靠譜
-等等，為什麼不靠譜？That's lame.Wait. Why is that lame?
額，我不知道
Uh, I don't know.[ Groans ]
白癡
[ Laughs ]Douche bag.
我對什麼事都不擅長，我只是盡力而為
I'm not good at everything.I just do my best at everything.
好嗎？事情就是這樣的
All right?That's what it's about.
我是說，你一直談論哲學之類的狗屁玩意
I mean, you talk about philosophyand shit all the time,
但是他真的做了什麼呢，啊？
but what has he really done, hmm?
你甚至有申請過大學嗎？
Have you even appliedto colleges yet?
不，但是我正要。。。正要申請
No, but I'm getting-I'm getting to it.
-耶，好吧，你是該申請，我是說。。。
-我在申請
Yeah, well, you should get to it.I'm just saying. I am.
你可以採納我的部分意見
You could use some of that.
你可以閉上鳥嘴，怎麼樣？
You could use some 鈥淪hut the hell up.鈥?How about that?
-你只是缺乏主動，這沒什麼大不了的
-是嗎？你“缺乏”雞巴
You just lack initiative.It's not that big- Oh, yeah? You lack a dick.
兄弟們，告訴我們這裡怎麼回事
Boys, please tell uswhat's going on here.
額，好的，這裡好像聖母瑪利亞出現了。。。
Uh, well, it would seem that aVirgin Mary has appeared...
在一名本地男子的煎餅糖漿裡
in the syrupof a local man's pancake.
不，沒有啊
[ Matt]No, it has not.
額，好吧，馬上就出現，好嗎？稍等
Uh, well, it will in a second, okay?Just hold on.
哦，現在肯定發生了某種超自然現象
Oh, that is definitely somesupernatural shit going on here.
額，不好意思，你能過來一下嗎？
Um, excuse me.Can you come here real quick?
額，你能看下這個嗎？
Um, can you just look at that?
哦，上帝啊！
（西班牙語）
Ay, Dios mio!
滾地球，用力過大了
Grounder.Too much pressure.
安德魯
Andrew.
哦，夥計，得了，別去弄她
[Andrew] Oh, dude. Come on.Leave her alone.
哦，你來真的？
Oh, seriously?
夥計！
Dude!
哦，拜託，這樣很不好
Oh, come on.That is so messed up.
-她要被炒魷魚了
-我不知道。。。
She's gonna get fired.I didn't know-
- 真噁心- 你們隊上會共用護襠嗎?
That is disgusting.But do you guys share cups on the team?
不 當然不共用護襠 老兄
No, we don't share cups, man.[Chuckles]
看到那車嗎?
You see that car though?
- 紅色的那輛- 看到了
The red one.Yeah.
口香糖那招挺酷的
[ Steve ] All right.The gum was cool.
你盡力了 但是算失敗的
All right. You tried.It was a failed attempt though.
看我的
Watch this.
- 你要幹什麼?- 看著
What are you doing?Watch.
去啊
[ Matt ]Go, go, go.
什麼?
[ Andrew ]What?
不會吧
No way!
媽的
[ Matt]Holy shit!
夥計 天啊
[Andrew]Dude! Holy crap!
怎麼樣? 怎麼樣?
What? What?
- 就是這麼回事- 有人看到嗎?
That's what I'm talking about!Did anybody see?
史蒂夫 蒙特加梅利當選班長
Steve Montgomery for president![ Grunts ]
- 我好像臉上流經血- 太噁心了
I'm having, like, a face period.[Andrew] Oh, man.
暫停
Pause.
夥計們 她來了
[Groans] You guys.You guys, here she comes.
她來了
Here she comes!Oh-
麥特 別盯著看 別看
[ Snickering ] [ Matt] Don't look.Don't look, don't look.
史蒂夫 別看
Steve, don't look.
她找不到...她以為被偷了
[ Steve ] She can't find-She thinks it's stolen.
她完全不知 沒錯 這次還真是那黑人幹的
She has no idea. [Steve] Yes,it was the black guy this time.
"我發誓我停在這的 我的車呢?"
[ High-pitched Voice] 鈥淚 could have swornI parked it right here. Where is my car?"
別理我們
Ignore us.
我們是...摩門教的
We're just...Mormons.
那啥意思?
[All Laughing] [Andrew] What does that mean?
[ Laughing ] What does that mean?[ Laughing ]
啊哦！啊哦！
[Andrew ]Uh-oh! Uh-oh!
加雷蒂快笑死了
Garetty's-Garetty's having a giggle fit.
那實在太了不起了
[ Shouting ] That wasso- It was amazing.
我懂 但別那麼激動
I know. Just take it easywith the merchandise.
在光天化日下 怎麼會沒人看見?
[ Matt] How did nobody see that?It was out in the open.
她的表情 我忘不掉她那表情
[Andrew] Her face!I cannot get her face out of my mind!
太棒了
[ Laughing ]That was awesome.
那是誰啊?
Who is this?
我有好多主意
So many ideasof stuff that we can do!
- 繞過去啊- 只是某個鄉巴佬混蛋
Go around.That's just some redneck asshole.
- 繞過去- 史蒂夫 史蒂夫
Go around. Steve, Steve, Steve, Steve.Take the camera. Take the camera.
拿著攝影機 拿著
All right. Just make sureit's zoomed out all the way.
好 確定鏡頭拉到最遠
[Steve] Got ya. I can see you.[ Matt] Okay, buddy.
- 知道了 我拍著呢- 好啦 兄弟
[ Horn Honking ]What you gonna do?
你要幹什麼?
[ Matt] What the hellis this guy's problem?
這傢伙有什麼問題啊?
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼?
Abracadabra!
安德魯 操
[ Matt] Whoa, whoa, whoa!Andrew, shit!
你他媽幹了什麼? 麥特 停車 停
What the hell did you just do?Matt, stop the car! Stop! Stop!
- 你瘋了嗎?- 開到路旁 我們得馬上下去
[ Matt] Are you crazy? Pull down the road.We gotta go down there right now.
夥計們 我很抱歉
[Andrew ]Guys, I'm sorry!
你做了什麼? 你為什麼那麼做?
What did you do?Why did you do that?
我不是故意的 我...
[Andrew] I didn't mean to.I didn't-
操 你有什麼毛病啊? 你看
Shit! What the hell is wrong with you?Look at this!
- 你放鬆好嗎?- 那人說不定還在車裡呢
Will you just calm down!The guy's probably still in there!
對不起 好嗎?
I'm sorry, okay?
- 安德魯 別 別- 但我...我可以幫忙
Andrew, stop, stop!But I can- I can help!
- 我可以救他出來- 你什麼都別做
I can get him out.Stop doing things!
史蒂夫 史蒂夫
Steve! Steve!
史蒂夫 小心!
Steve, be careful!
操操
Shit! Shit!
我的天啊 安德魯 你開什麼玩笑?
Oh, my God, Andrew.Are you kidding me?
史蒂夫
[Andrew Panting ]Steve!
天啊 天啊
[Andrew Whispering ] Oh, God.Oh, God.
他媽的
Goddamn it!
史蒂夫
Steve!
安德魯
Andrew! Oh-[Andrew Panting ]
操
Shit!
操操操
Shit, Shit, Shit, Shit!
麥特 他救到他了 他救到了...
Oh, Matt, he's got him!He's got him. He's got-
幫我一把
Help me.
我抓著他的背
I'll get in back of him.
把他弄上去
Get him up.
等等 史蒂夫 看著他我去找幫手
Hang on. Steve, stay with him.I'm gonna go get some help.
- 你在報警嗎?- 對
Are you calling the cops?Yeah, yeah.
- 你別吵好嗎? 我聽不到- 你快掛電話好嗎?
Will you stop? I can't hear them.Will you hang up the phone?
- 是的 就在白彎橋旁- 麥特 他沒事的
Yeah. It's just down past, uh, WhiteCrescent Bridge. Matt, he's fine.
- 麥特 他沒事- 是的 是的
Matt, he's fine.Yeah. Yeah.
- 麥特- 別吵 我聽不到...
Fine, Matt! Stop!Stop! I can't hear-
喂
[ Thunder Rumbles ]Hey!
喂 在這裡
[ Sirens Approaching ]Hey! Hey! Over here!
-...衝破了護欄- 喂 那開著嗎?
...Peeled off the road and went straightthrough the guardrail. Hey, is that on?
- 你認為這是遊戲嗎?- 我不懂你們為什麼這麼生氣
...This is a game or something?I don't understand how you guys can be so angry.
你不懂我們為什麼生氣?
You don't understandhow we can be angry?
安德魯 你把人送進醫院了耶
Andrew, you- you put somebodyin the hospital tonight, okay?
你不明白嗎?
Do you understand that?
安德魯 看著我 你讓人進醫院了
Andrew, look at me.You put a guy in the hospital!
對此你有什麼感覺? 你傷害別人了
How do you feel about that?You hurt somebody!
媽的 我們需要定幾條規則 好嗎?
[ Sighs ] Shit.We need rules, okay?
第一條: 不准用在生物上
Rule number one:No using it on living things.
第二條: 不能在生氣時用 就是這麼回事
Rule number two: You can't use itwhen you're angry. That's it.
第三條: 我認為我們不該在公共場所用或者告訴別人這事
Rule number three: I don't think we should beusing it in public or telling anybody about it.
- 你不能就自己定規則 好嗎?- 我就是要定規則
Look, you can't just declare rules, okay?I will declare rules-
- 是你說沒關係的- 我要定規則
You're the one that said that nothing matters.I will declare rules.
我們如果要繼續下去 能力又越來越強的話我們需要規則
If we're gonna keep going, and we'regetting stronger, we need rules.
我們需要規則 對吧?
We need rules, right?
麥特是對的 我們需要規則
[ Steve]Matt's right. We need rules.
安德魯 接那該死的電話
[ Father]Andrew! Answer the goddamn phone!
安德魯
[ Ringing Continues ]Andrew!
麥特 他怎麼說的?
Matt, what did he say?
你還在生我的氣嗎??
Are you still mad at me?
- 不 我沒生氣- 你看起來在生氣
No, I'm not mad.Well, you seem mad.
我沒生氣 我只是...
I'm not mad. I just-
我只是覺得我們應該更小心 懂嗎? 我們不能...
I just think that we need to be morecareful now, you know? We can't-
我們必須多考慮清楚 不能就直接做要先想清楚 好嗎?
We have to think a little bit more.We can't just do things. We have to think first, okay?
- 我懂- 好的
I understand.Okay.
史蒂夫在這鬼地方幹什麼?
[ Matt] Why is Steve out in the boonies?[ Chuckles ]
這是哪裡?
Where are we?
史蒂夫?
Steve?
他的車在這啊
[Andrew ]His car's right there.
對啊 史蒂夫 你在哪?
Yeah.Steve, where you at?
史蒂夫
[ Andrew ]Steve!
"往上看"
鈥淟ook up.鈥?
你好啊 孩子們
[ Steve ]Hello, boys.
不會吧
[Andrew] What? [ Laughing ]
- 怎麼樣?- 不 不
What is up?No. No.
等等 夥計們 聽我說
Wait, guys. Wait, wait, wait.Check me out. Hear me out.
- 你在飛耶- 我的媽啊
You're flying![ Matt] Holy shit!
- 等等 等等 聽我說 聽我說- 不會吧 不會吧
Wait, wait, wait. Hear me out.Hear me out. No way! No way!
你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
比看上去簡單 我發誓 比看上去簡單
It's much easier than it looks. I swear.It's much easier than it looks.
我的天啊 夥計
[Andrew]Oh, my God, dude.
你要確定能支撐自己 別跳...不然你會翻過去- 我懂了
Make sure you catch yourself. Don't try and jump,or you'll just flip yourself. I got it. I got it.
- 來吧 麥特- 好的
Come on, Matt. Come on.All right.
該死
Oh, shit![ Laughing ]
靠啊，哥們！
Oh, man!
摔個狗吃屎你怎麼不到我後面去
Eating dirt, man.Why don't you get behind me?
- 你礙到我了- 什麼意思?
You were in my way.What do you mean?
想想“鷂”式飛機“想想“鷂”式飛機“
Think Harrier jet.Think Harrier jet.
靠啊，哥們
[ Laughing ]Oh, man.
- 他媽的- 你還好嗎?
Goddamn it!Are you okay?
- 我看著你- 讓我集中精神
[ Matt] I'm watching.Just let me concentrate.
- 專心- 好啦 等一下
[Steve] Focus! Focus!Okay! Hold on.
那是你專心的表情嗎?
[ Matt]Is that your focus face?
我的天啊 夥計
Oh, my God, dude.
哇哦！狗屁！
Whoo!Bullshit!
- 我飛起來了- 開什麼玩笑?
I'm up! I'm up!Are you kidding me?
- 天啊- 撐住
Holy crap! [ Steve ] Hold it!Hold it!
- 我做到了 老兄- 媽呀 夥計
Oh, my God, dude. I am doing it.Holy crap, dude.
就是這樣 你做到了
Yeah! [Steve] That's it, man.You're doing it.
哇哈！
Whoo-hoo!
安德魯 別放屁不然我們永遠追不上你了
Okay. Okay. Andrew, don't fart.We'll never find you again.
抓住我 抓住我
Steve, stop me.Stop me, stop me.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.Whoa, whoa.
- 你現在在飛- 你們倆看起來真可愛
You are flying now.You guys look so cute together.
我要帶著攝影機上去了 好嗎?
Whoa! I'm coming up.I'm bringing the camera, okay?
好
All right.[ Stumbling ]
好吧 我們怎麼下去?
[Andrew] All right.How do we get down?
哇哈！耶！
Whoo-hoo! [ Andrew ] Yeah!
安德魯 這裡冷死人了
[ Matt] Andrew!It's freezing up here!
我聽不到
I can't hear you.[ Laughing ]
超速啟動
Activate hyperdrive!
哇！
Whoo!
我們到底在哪?
[ Steve Laughing ]Where the hell are we?
- 快跟上 來啊- 什麼?
Catch up! Let's go!What?
這太瘋狂了
[ Steve ]Whoo! This is insane!
哇哈！
Whoo-hoo!
- 夥計- 好了 安德魯
Dude!All right, Andrew!
哇！
Whoo!
- 你是鬼了- 小心
[ Matt ] Tag, you're it![ Chuckles ] Watch out.
煞車！哇！啊！
[ Steve ] Pump the brakes!Whoa! Aah!
嘿 麥特 你終於有個長項了
Hey, Matt! You're finallygood at something!
很簡單的 好耶
[ Matt]it's so easy! Yeah!
啊！耶！
Aah! [Steve Laughs] Yeah!
哇！
Whoo!
嗚啊！
[ Grunts ] [Andrew ] Whoa!
接到了
Got it!
準備接球，寶貝！
Tebow time, baby!
好耶
Yeah!
漂亮 史蒂夫
Oh! [ Matt] Nice hands, Steve!
- 得分- 扔回來
[ Andrew ] Touchdown!Throw it back to Daddy!
夥計 接的好
Oh, dude. Nice catch, man! Yes!
- 史蒂夫 再遠一點- 嘿 麥特
[ Chuckles ]
你聽到那聲音嗎?
[ Matt ] Steve!Go deep! Hey, Matt!
那是什麼?
Do you hear that?[ Rumbling ]
史蒂夫
What is that?
媽的 差點死了 夥計 天啊
Whoa! Steve!
我差點死了 夥計 差點...我靠，我靠
Oh, shit. Almost died, dude.Holy shit. Holy shit.
差點死了，夥計！差點。。。
Almost died, man! Almost-
安德魯 你救了我一命
Andrew, you saved my life!
我的天啊 你救了我一命
[ Chuckling ] Oh, my God.You saved my life!
我的天啊 你救了我的命
[ Mock Screaming ]Oh, God, you saved my life!
喔 天啊
Oh, my God![ Mock Kissing Sound ]
好的我靠
Okay.Holy shit.
那是攝影機嗎? 你把我和攝影機都救了?
Is that the camera?You saved me and the camera?
告訴我你全部都錄下來了...
Please tell me you got that on tape!You have to-
媽的
Ah, shit.[ Gasping ]
- 搞什麼...- 我們活著
What the hell- [Laughing ] We're alive!
- 什麼叫怎麼回事?- 你沒看到發生了什麼事?
What do you mean? The hell happened?You didn't see what happened?
媽的 安德魯 安德魯 你是個天才
Oh, shit! Andrew!Andrew! You're a genius!
我們得看一看...
We got to see this! Holy-
好的，哦，我靠
All right. Oh. Holy shit.
等等，哦，上帝！我們落地了，耶！
Wait. Oh, God!We're on the ground. Yes!
哇！
[ Laughing ]Whoo!
我們創了歷史
We have broken history!
我是說 自山頂洞人時代以來...
I mean, I'm talking aboutsince the caveman times.
還有埃及人啊 萊特兄弟...
Uh, the Egyptians,the Wright brothers.
過來 麥特 進來 進來
Come here, Matt. Come here.Get in here. Get in.
說出來 "我會飛"
Say it. 鈥淚 can fly.鈥?
- 我會飛- 我會飛
I can fly.I can fly!
- 拜託- 發自內心地說
Oh, come on.Say it with your chest!
- 我會飛- 大聲說 麥特
I can fly!Say it, Matt.
- 喊出來- 我會飛
Shout it out!I can fly!
我會飛 我會飛
I can fly! I can fly!
我想救你的 安德魯只是比我快
[ Matt] I tried to save you, man.Andrew was just quicker. [ Laughing ]
再來一次如何？
[Andrew ]How does that go again?
我們差點死了
We almost died.
拜託喔
Oh, please.Gestures-
她怎麼會沒察覺?
How does shenot notice though?
我們說真的 夥計們
Come on.Let's be serious, guys.
她當然察覺到比以前更爽
She definitely noticedthat it's gotten better.
- 你需要 你知道...- 怎樣?
You just gotta be, you know-Yeah?
你要做微妙的改變
You just gotta be subtle.
你真酷啊
[ Laughs ]That is so cool.
夥計 我自從暑假就沒做過愛了
Dude. And I haven'thad sex since summer.
我從沒做過愛
I haven't had sex since ever.
真的嗎?
Really?Really?
這我實在無法接受
That is completely unacceptable.Well-
你們怎麼忍得住 怎麼忍得住 夥計?
How are you guys so cool?How are you guys so cool, man?
液氮冷卻小弟弟的吧
Liquid nitrogen.[ Laughing ]
嘿 夥計們
[ Matt ]Hey, guys?
夥計們 你們還醒著嗎?
[Snorting ]Guys? You guys up?
是啊
[Andrew ]Yeah.
嘿 今天真是...
Hey, uh-Today was like-
我覺得是我一生中最美好的一天
It was like, I think,the best day of my life.
我是說...
Like, I mean-
我回想起來 實在想不出...
I'm thinking about it,and I can't think of any day...
有比今天更讓我快樂的一天 知道嗎?
that I liked betterthan today, you know?
我真的...真的這麼認為
I really- I think it was.
是啊
Yeah.
一致贊同
Unanimous.[ Chuckles ]
沒錯
Yes.
好啊 很好
Okay. Good.
好 聽著 不管你們怎麼說...
[Steve] Okay, check this out.Say what you want,
我想要這個週末飛去茂宜島
but I'm thinking about booking itto Maui for the weekend.
- 如何?- 真的嗎?
What's up with that?Seriously?
反正我們做得到 我也想過類似的事...
Well, we could do it. I mean,I was thinking the same thing,
只不過我一直嚮往去西藏
except I've alwayswanted to go to Tibet.
- 為什麼是西藏?- 西藏?
Why Tibet?Tibet?
我也不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
應該很美麗 你知道嗎? 很多的...
It seems really beautiful,you know, with all the-
你閉嘴好嗎? 閉嘴...
Will you shut up? Shut-
那些紀念碑和山峰 你知道嗎?
The monuments and mountains, you know?Mm-hmm.
況且那些喇嘛們已達到了如此高深的啟示...
I don't know. And the monks have achievedsuch a high level of enlightenment...
他們還會飄浮之類的 你知道嗎?
that they can, like,float and shit, you know?
- 所以我們可以輕易融入- 我們也可以耍耍他們
So we would fit right in.We could really mess with their heads as well.
不過說真的 我認為我們應該去
Yeah, but, like, seriously,I think we should go.
會挺酷的 也很平靜
It would be really cool.Peaceful.
不 我覺得是個很好的主意我還真的挺想去的
No, I think it's a really good idea.I actually would like to go.
我贊成 你呢 史蒂夫?
I'm down.You down, Steve?
啥? 我不知道 老兄
What-I-I don't know, man.
在西藏不穿比基尼 所以我不知道我贊不贊成
There's no bikinis in Tibet.So I don't know if I'm down with that.
真是聰明啊，棒極了，她可能已經丟了工作
It was brilliant. Ch, it was so amazing.She might have lost her job.
哦，糟了，夥計，今天是我老媽生日，我得走了
Oh, shit, dude.I got my mom's birthday. I gotta go.
-今天是德布阿姨的生日？-是啊，我得走了，我得走了
It's Aunt Deb's birthday today?Yeah. I gotta go. I gotta go.
-替我問候她-回見，麥特
Tell her I said hi.Later, Matt.
好吧，你們現在想幹嘛？你們想去哪兒？
All right, what do you want to do now?Where do you want to go?
我不知道，我是說，我不想回家
I don't know. I mean,I don't want to go home.
你們想去城裡嗎？
Oh, do you wantto go into the city?
-不行，現在是高峰時期，兄弟，會有很多車-那又如何？
Nah, it's rush hour, bro.It's gonna be so much traffic. So what?
說得對哥們，我們走！
Oh, yeah. That's right.Duh! Let's go.
喔 嘿 抱歉 我只是...
Oh, hey. Sorry, I just-
嗨
Hi.
你介意被拍嗎?
Do you mind if I film you?
一點點 我不是很喜歡上鏡頭
Uh, a little bit. I don't reallylike being on camera actually.
說不定越上越習慣
Well, maybe it's,like, exposure therapy.
不 我來只是要給你一個東西
Yeah. No, I just came byto give you something actually.
- 是嗎?- 是啊
You did?Yeah.
什麼?
What?
我看了你的...
I was watching your, um-
你的...你知道 你的博客
your-your-you know, your blog?
在中非共和國有個旱災 對吧?
There's a droughtin the Central African Republic, right?
我看到你寫的 感覺不錯 而且不太貴...
Yeah. So I saw that and I thought itseems pretty cool, and it's cheap too,
所以我想說何不呢?
so I thought why not?
- 可不是嗎- 是啊
Totally.Yeah.
是啊 我看得出你對全球的這種大事...
[ Phone Beeps] Yeah, I can tell thatyou're really global and big picture,
- 還挺關心的- 對
concerned about that kind of stuff.Yeah.
你知道 麥特 這你可以自己寄出去的
You know, Matt, you canjust mail this yourself.
我不是你媽
I'm not your mom.
好吧 我是說 我只是...
Okay. I mean, I just-
這是怎麼搞的? 這是改頭換面的你嗎?
What is this?Is this, like, the new you?
中一時你高高在上的 現在算什麼?
You got too smart to have funin eighth grade. So now what?
不是的
No.
凱西
Casey, Casey, Casey,Casey, Casey, Casey.
聽著 聽著 我可以跟你談一談嗎?
Listen, listen. Can Ijust talk to you for a second?
我可以告訴你一些事嗎?
Can I just tell you something?Mm-hmm.
我只是...我...
I just- I-I-
我想讓你知道 我不是以前的那個我了
I just want you to knowI'm not, you know, who I was- now.
-你懂嗎 我沒事了 我...
You know, I'm cool.I'm just-
你沒事?
You're cool?
高中比人氣這回事像是古怪的競賽...
High school popularity just seemedlike this weird backward contest,
我當時以為我看清了這一點就...
and I thought sinceI knew that, I could just-
就等於你比其他人都優越
That made you betterthan everybody else.
不 不 不是的
No. No, no, no.
- 我懂你的意思- 我儘量不去接觸那些
I know what you mean.I would separate myself from that.
- 我懂- 你懂嗎?
I get it.You get it?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我知道聽起來很怪 我只是希望你知道這點
I know it sounds weird.I just wanted you to know that.
知道你沒事了
To know that you're cool.
哇 我真的搞砸了 是吧
Wow, I really screwed this up.
沒你想像的那麼糟
Not as muchas you might think.
- 真的嗎?- 再見
Really?Good-bye.
- 凱西...- 我得走了 拜
Casey-I gotta go. Bye.
真是的
[ Matt Groans ]Come on.
夥計 你什麼時候開始這樣弄的?
[Steve] Dude!When did you start doing this?
- 什麼時候?- 怎麼 你說攝影機嗎?
Like, since when?What, with the camera?
是的 你的攝影機
Yes, with the camera.Um-
我也不記得 我想有一段時間了吧
I don't know. It's beena little while, I guess.
我就沒法那麼做
See- Oh.I can't do that.
我沒法做那種靈巧的事
I can't do stuffthat requires finesse.
昨天我試著打出我的名字結果把鍵盤給折了
I tried to type my name out yesterday,and I cracked my keyboard in half.
不 夥計 其實很簡單就想像你用手拿著它
No, dude. it's really easy.You just- You think that you're holding it.
-你看，這就是我所要說的
-什麼？See, that's what I'm talkingabout right there. What?
你總是在想一些我們能做的新招式，夥計
You're always thinking upnew shit that we can do, man.
-這太瘋狂了，你知道嗎
-我是說。。。
This is insane.You know- I mean-
是啊，是啊
Yeah.Yeah.
是啊，是的，我想我是的
Yeah. Yes. I guess that I am.
哦！
Whoo!
老媽像是永遠不會回家了
Mom's, like, never home any more.
我是說，你看我爸那個樣子，他就這樣安靜地。。。
I mean, you sawhow my dad is. He's just... quiet.
閑坐著
Sits around.
跟他說這些都沒意義，因為他沒什麼可說的
And it's pointless to talk to him about it'cause he's got... nothing to say.
你看，這不一樣 因為你一直都很有人緣
See, it's different,'cause you've always had friends,
大家都想跟你聊天 跟你相處
and people want to talk to youand be around you.
我從來沒有過 我是說 在這之前...
I never had any of that.I mean, before this,
我跟麥特都不怎麼相處了他還是我表兄呢
I barely even hung out with Matt, and he's my cousin.[Sirens Walling In Distance]
我們小時候時很親近 但...
We were closewhen we were little, but-
我不知道 到了高中後 一切都改變了
I don't know.In high school, everything changed.
去過太空針塔嗎？
（西雅圖地標建築）
Ever beento the Space Needle?
有啊，好像我5歲時去的
Yep. When I was, like, five.
那是給遊客看的
it's for tourists.
額，我不知道，我是說，我去了。。。
Well, I don't know.I mean, I went, um-
我好像是7歲去的
I think I was, like, seven-
有一次跟我老爸
with my dad one time and-
我不知道，那真的是美好的一天
I don't know.It was actually a really good day.
你記得嗎？
You remember that?
是啊，我記得
Yeah.Actually, I do.
你知道嗎，我一直想問你的
You know, I've beenmeaning to ask you.
寒假快到了
Winter break is coming up.
你應該跟我一起參加才藝秀
You should dothe talent show with me.
不可能
No way.
何不? 這會對你很好的
Why not? lt'd be good for youto get out there, you know.
- 認識些朋友 認識些女孩- 夥計 我不...這不...
Meet some people, meet some girls.Dude, I'm not- it's just not-
- 怎樣?- 我就是很害羞 好嗎?
What? Look, I'm justreally shy, okay?
還有 我根本沒有任何才藝
And I don't-I don't even have any talents, so-
你在說啥呢? 你當然有才藝
What are you talking about, youdon't have- You have talent.
你有才藝
You've got talent.
夥計 不可能吧
Oh, dude, no way.
你看起來很帥
[ Chuckles ] [ Mother]You look handsome.
謝謝 史蒂夫...
[ Coughing ]Thanks, yes. Steve-
把他的衣服借給我，好讓我看起來酷一點還是什麼的
[Coughing Continues] let me borrow some of hisclothes to make me look cool or whatever.
我很高興你這麼常跟朋友們相處
I'm glad you're spendingso much time with your friends.
是啊 我也是
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
- 喂- 怎樣?
[ Father] Hey. What?
你是怎麼上學的?
How are you getting to school?
- 我不懂你的意思- 別跟我胡扯 你這白癡
I don't know what you mean.Don't bullshit me, you idiot.
麥特都不過來了 沒看到他的車
Matt doesn't come.He doesn't drive up.
你自己外出 是誰載你去學校的?
You leave the house.Who the hell's giving you rides to school?
- 麥特- 好吧 你知道嗎?
M-Matt.All right. You know what?
你在騙我
You're lying.
不知道你在幹什麼 但你藏不了的
You're up to something,and you can't hide it.
你以為你可以偷偷摸摸的嗎?
You thinkyou can just slink, hmm?
笑咪咪的在我的屋簷下摸進摸出的?
Sneak in, sneak aroundmy house, smiling?
我看准你了
I'm onto your shit.
這蠢東西到底怎麼操作啊?
[Crowd Noise] [ Matt] How do youeven work this stupid thing?
好戲準備上場了
[Applause ]Ah! And we're in business.
- 嘿- 嗨
Hey. [Chuckles] Hi.
你來幹什麼?
Um, what are you doing here?
我在拍才藝秀啊
I'm filming for the talent show.
- 麥特 加雷蒂來拍才藝秀?- 沒錯
Matt Garetty is filming forthe talent show. Yes, I am.
哇
[ Chuckles ]Wow.
這算什麼 新發現的校園精神嗎?
What is this, some kind ofnewfound school spirit?
自己被人拍感覺如何?
How do you like it, huh?Being on camera? [ Feedback ]
- 我自己其實不排斥上鏡頭- 開始了
- I actually don't mind being on camera.- Oh. Here we go.
女士們 先生們 即將上臺的...
Ladies and gentlemen,now coming to the stage-
- 怎麼? 不用一套哲學來回我嗎?- 班長史蒂夫 蒙特加梅利
What? No philosophical comeback for me?Steve Montgomery
你最好把這錄下來
You're probably gonnawant to get this on camera.
大家好 準備看個才藝秀了嗎?
JJ [Rock] [Steve] C.V.High, you guys ready for a talent show?
我的學弟妹們 大聲點 這不夠大聲
All my underclassmen, come on.Make some noise. That's not loud enough.
我的學長姐們怎麼樣? 也來點聲音吧
How about my upperclassmen?Come on. Make some noise!
耶，史蒂夫！
[Cheering ] [ BOY] Yeah, Steve!
我的同學們 2012年的畢業班級呢?
Let me hear it from my seniors, class of 2012![ Loud Cheering ]
耶，噓
Yeah. Shh.
我要你們熱烈歡迎 年經又非常有才華的安德魯 戴特摩先生
Now I want you guys to give it up for theyoung and very talented Mr. Andrew Detmer.
-上場了-快，大夥
[ Matt] And you're on.[Steve] Come on, y'all.
-你們在幹什麼?-我們走！我們走！
[Casey] What are you guys doing?[ Steve] Let's go, let's go!
你們在欺負你表弟嗎?
Are you playing a prank on your cousin?[ Matt Chuckles]
這太壞了 麥特
That's mean, Matt.[Jeering Continues]
看就對了
[ Matt]Just watch.
真的？
[ Female Student]Really?
他在做什麼?
[ Male Student] Good luck![Casey] What's he doing?
我們要看才藝
[ Female Student]Show us some talent!
真好啊 麥特
[Audience Laughs]Nice, Matt.
把它們撿起來！撿起來！
Fifty-two Pickup!Pick 'em up!
不會吧
[Audience Gasps][Casey] No way!
耶！
[ Matt ]Yeah!
嗚！
Whoo!
安德魯加油
Go, Andrew!
怎麼可能?
[ Casey ]What? What?
- 他要走在那上面嗎??- 你想呢?
Are they gonna walk on that?[ Matt] What do you think?
哇哦！他沒事 他沒事
[Audience Gasps] Whoa. He's got it.He's got it. He's got it.
小心
Easy.
你可以的
Yeah, you got it.
天啊
[ Casey ]Holy crap!
耶！小菜一碟！
Yeah! Cakewalk![ Loud Applause ]
鼓掌，鼓掌，鼓掌！
[Steve]Give it up, give it up, give it up!
天啊 安德魯太驚人了
[ Casey Squeals]Oh, my God. Andrew is so amazing.
哇哦！
Whoa![ Laughs ]
鼓掌！響起來！
[ Loud Cheering ]Give it up! Let's go!
- 說真的 他是怎麼辦到的?- 我不知道
Seriously, how are they doing this?I don't know.
魔法吧
Magic.
嗚！
Whoo!
太神奇了
[ Casey ] That was amazing!Yeah!
嗚啊！安德魯！
[ Casey] Whoo! Whoo! Andrew!
- 天啊 我看得出來你腦袋快爆炸了- 什麼?
Oh, my God. I can see your head is, like,exploding right now. [Andrew ] What?
這就是你的驕傲的瓦解 現在開始
This is the beginning of your downfall.Hubris. Right there.
什麼驕傲?
What's hubris?Ha, ha, ha.
- 不 驕傲是什麼意思 麥特?- 你說真的?
No, what does “hubris” mean, Matt? Seriously?
- 那又是什麼意思?- 啥? 我...
What does “seriously” mean? What? I'm.
- 快走啊- 別推我 夥計 我走著呢
Get in there.Don't push me, dude. I'm going.
你的粉絲都在等你 你是今晚的大明星
Your fans await.You're the man of the hour.
- 看看這房子- 太正了
Look at this house!Oh, sick!
- 夥計 這地方好大- 是啊
Dude, this place looks huge.I know.
- 太大了- 夥計
It's enormous.Dude.
麥特 安德魯
[ Steve ]Matt! Andrew!
哦，天啊！哦，天啊！史蒂夫，天啊！
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!Steve! Oh, my God!
- 大夥都傻了- 來吧 大家都在等你
Everybody's freaking out. Come on, man.Everybody's been waiting for you.
給貴賓讓路 讓個路！
V.l.P. coming through.Coming through!
大魔術家安德魯到了
Andrew Copperfieldcoming through!
讓開 讓開
Make way, make way.
麥特 安德魯 來這邊
Matt, come this way.Drew, over here.
安德魯 戴特摩來了
Andrew Detmer'sin the house!
- 你感覺如何?- 我 我很好啊
[Andrew] How are you feeling?I'm-I'm- I'm doing good.
- 是嗎? 你確定嗎?- 嘿
Yeah? Are you sure? Are you sure?[Girl] Hey. Hey.
- 你好- 安德魯
Hello.Andrew.
- 你的魔術太帥了- 哇 謝了
Magic is so hot.Oh, wow. Thanks.
你完全不記得我嗎?
So, do you not remember me at all?Um-
- 摩妮卡 對吧? 摩妮卡?- 對
Monica, right? Monica.Yes!
...把攝影機放下我在放呢
...Setting the camera down.I'm setting the camera down.
什麼。。。哦
What-Oh.
借過
Oh. [ Singsong ] Excuse me.
你有沒有玩過那邊那遊戲?
Have you ever played that, over there?[ Chanting ]
呃 沒有 我沒玩過
Uh, no. I have neverplayed that, over there.
- 沒有嗎?- 從沒有過
No?Never.
我賭你一定很會玩
I bet you're good at it.Uh-
- 怎樣 不就是把球丟進杯子裡嗎?- 是啊
What, you just throw the ballinto the cups? Yep. Yep.
- 我是應該滿會玩的- 是嗎?
I actually could be goodat that right now. Yeah?
- 或許吧- 試過才知
Maybe.Let's find out.
- 不 不 不- 來吧
No, no, no, no, no.Come on!
- 什麼?- 來啊
What?Come on.
- 好吧- 來吧
Okay, okay.Come on.
好啦 我來了
Okay, I'm coming.I'm coming.
你在這啊
There you are.[Clicks Tongue]
棒極了
Amazing.
這就對了
[ Steve ]That's what I'm talking about.
耶！哇哈！
[ Matt]Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
喂 安德魯到底在哪?
Hey, where is Andrew anyway?
哦
Oh.[ Chuckles ]
安德魯和那粉紅頭髮的女孩上樓了
Andrew's upstairs with the girlwith the pink hair.
怎麼 他們一起上去的?
What, like, they went together?
我的好小子 當然一起上去的你在說什麼?
That's my boy. Of course they went together.What are you talking 'bout?
嘿 安德魯 希望你看得到
Hey, Andrew.I hope you're seeing this.
恭喜你 先生
Congratulations, sir.
我想讓你知道 夥計...
I just wanted you to know, dude-
在這之前 我真的挺擔心你 你知道嗎?
I was really worried about youbefore all this, you know?
但夥計 從今以後一切都會好轉了
But, dude, things are gonna getso much better for you now.
我真的這麼認為
I really, really feel that.
然後我要告訴你 我愛你 知道嗎?
And I want you to knowI love you, you know?
我愛你 夥計 你和我
I love you, man.It's you and me.
戴特摩和加雷蒂，一輩子的表親
It's Detmer and Garetty,extended family for life.
-喔 抱歉，抱歉-哦，沒事沒事
Oh, sorry. Sorry. [Girl] No, man.Excuse yourself.
喔，夥計
Oh, man.
- 什麼時候變成是我在那裡自拍的傢伙?- 嘿 麥特
When did I become the one who's outhere filming myself? Hey, Matt.
嘿 凱西
Oh, hey. Hey, Casey.
你在拍什麼?
So what are you filming?
只是隨便拍拍
Uh, it's just a thing.
不是什麼頭號新聞之類的
It's not likeeye of the storm or anything.
我只是...我想告訴你...
Hey, I wanted to-I wanted to tell you...
我最近...最近讓我想了很多
I've really been-it's been making me think a lot.
我最近生活中常想到...
I've been kind ofthinking about it in my-
不 我說真的 我的生活中
No, I have. Like, in my life.
我在想 如果我認真付出能做到的事
I've been thinking, if I applied myself,what I could do.
我可以...我真的可以改變世界
I could really-I could change the world.
- 我是說 真的很...- 你醉了
I mean, it's really been-You're drunk.
什麼?
What?
嘿 凱西?
[ Chuckles ]Hey, Casey?
差不多高二開始 我就算是一直在注意你
I've basically been stalking yousince, like, sophomore year.
抱歉 用詞不對 我不該說"注意"...
Sorry, use of the word 鈥渟talking.鈥?I shouldn't have said-
想不想離開這?
You want to get out of here?
- 好啊- 好嗎?
Yeah.Yeah?
好的 當然好
Yes. Yes, definitely.
呃 我必須先把攝影機還回去
Uh, I-I have to drop offthe camera first though.
好了 大家準備好目擊歷史了沒?
Okay, you guys are getting readyto witness history, all right?
我現在像個驕傲的老爸因為在這扇門後...
I'm like a proud dad right nowbecause behind these doors,
安德魯 戴特摩要成為男人了
Andrew Detmer becomes a man.
他還是個害怕的小男孩
He's a little boy behind there.He's scared.
像個等著破蛹而出的蝴蝶...
He's like a butterfly,getting ready to emerge-
- 噢 天啊- 還是什麼類似的狗屁
[Monica ] Oh, God!from a cocoon or some shit like that.
噁心的怪胎
Disgusting weirdo!
等等 怎麼搞的?
Wait. What happened?Ha-ha. Okay-
- 那是...- 快滾開
Is that-Out of my way now!
-噢 真是的-莫妮卡，發生什麼了？
Oh, man.[Andrew ] Monica, what happened?
安德魯 沒事的 夥計 別在意
Drew! Drew! It's okay, man.Don't worry about it.
- 聽著 任誰都有可能發生- 夥計
Look, it happens to thebest of us, okay? Dude!
你喝了太多...
You hada little too much to drink-
朋友...
You- Oh. Oh. Whoa, buddy.
- 怎麼回事 夥計?- 你在笑什麼?
The hell's going on, dude?Why are you laughing?
真是的 還弄上了我的衣服
Aw, man.All over my jacket.
- 別 別笑了- 你在說什麼?
Stop. Stop laughing.What are you talking about?
- 沒關係的 老兄- 不 沒有沒關係 史蒂夫 別
It's cool, man.No, it's not cool, Steve. Stop.
- 別怎樣 沒事的- 你可以出去嗎?
Stop what? It's cool, man.Will you just get out of here?
- 滾 你有什麼毛病啊?- 安德魯
Get out! What's your problem?Drew, Drew!
- 你覺得這很好笑嗎?- 不 我不是在笑...
You think this is funny?No, I'm not laughing-
快滾
Get out!
爸
Dad![ Thunderclap ]
安德魯 求你了 我需要我的藥
[Mother] Andrew! Please!I need my medicine.
媽在受苦 懂嗎? 她需要藥 你在哪裡?
Mom's in pain, all right?She needs her pills! Where are you?
你在哪裡?
[Andrew] Where are you?[Coughing Continues]
爸
Dad!
你媽快死了，你自己卻藏個$500的攝影機?你是有多自私?
Hoarding a $500 camera while your mom dies in there?I mean, how selfish can you be?
我看過你拍的東西
I went through your camera.
你看到了什麼?
What did you see?
看到你像個廢物
Just you being a loser.
你以為那些人是你的朋友嗎?
You think that those peopleare your friends?
他們不是
Huh? They're not.
你是個恥辱
You're an embarrassment.
你到處跑來跑去，花我的錢
You're running around this town,spending my money.
我對你說話時你看著我
Look at mewhen I'm talking to you!
我沒花你的錢 理查
I didn't spend anyof your money, Richard.
因為我沒錢給你花
'Cause I don't havea dime to spend.
每一分...看著我
Every last cent-Look at me!
- 每一分都花在你的學校上...- 學校?
Every last cent goes toschool for you- School?
- 還有你媽的藥- 我上的是公立學校
And medication for your mother.I go to a public school!
- 我連一個該死的...- 公立學校是不收錢的 你這白癡
I can't even pay for a goddamn- You don'tpay for a public school, you idiot!
你叫我什麼?
What did you call me?
你叫我白癡嗎 你這人渣?
Did you call mean idiot, you shit?
你叫我白癡嗎? 啊?
Did you call me an idiot? Huh?
你這死人渣
You piece of shit!
起來 我叫你起來
Get up. I said get up!
起來
Get up!
- 我可以把你捏碎 你知道嗎?- 住手
I could crush you, you know that?Stop it!
捏碎
Crush you! Get- [ Grunts ]
笑一個 麥特
[ Casey]Smile, Matt.
我的天啊 麥特
Oh, my God, Matt. Oh. [Coughs]
現在可不可以先別拍 拜託?
Can we not do the camera thingright now, please?
發生了什麼事?
What happened?[ Sighs ]
呃 就突然開始的
Uh- It just startedout of nowhere.
你沒事嗎?
Are you okay?[ Exhales ]
我頭挺痛的
My head hurts really bad.[Chuckles]
那應該又是史蒂夫打給你的
That's probably Stevecalling your cell again.
我待會再回他電
I'll call him back later.
我想現在先...
I think it's time to take-[ Screams ]
麥特！麥特！
Matt! Matt! Come on! Oh, wow.I did not expect this.
Give me my-Whoa!
喂 喂 混帳
[ Steve ]Hey! Hey, asshole!
你在這裡幹什麼?
What are you doing up here?
別管我 史蒂夫
Just leave me alone,Steve!
你不該上來的 很不安全
You can't be up here, dude.This isn't safe.
我不想跟別人說話
I don't want to talk to anyone.
老兄 你在這幹什麼?
Bro! What are youdoing up here?
別管我
Leave me alone!
你是怎麼找到我的?
How did you find me?[ Thunderclap ]
我也不知道 夥計 我鼻子流血
I don't know, man.My nose was bleeding.
我似乎聽到了你的聲音...
I heard your voiceor something like-
你的臉怎麼回事?
What the hellhappened to your face?
沒事 夥計 別管我
Nothing, man.Just leave me alone.
那可不是沒事 那...是你爸
No, dude, that's not nothing.That- Your dad!
你爸又痛揍你 他不能再這麼對待你了
Your dad beat the shit out of you.He can't do that to you now.
你別裝得一付你很關心的樣子 好吧?
Will you stop actinglike you give a shit?
夥計 你為什麼這麼對我說話?我是你最好的朋友啊
Dude. Why are you talking to me like this?I'm your best friend.
我沒有朋友
I don't have any friends!
在這之前 你從來不是我的朋友
You were never my friendbefore any of this.
我和你還有麥特每天都在一起啊
I hang out with you and Matt,like, every day!
我們約好了要一起環遊世界的你...你不記得嗎?
We're supposed to fly around the world together.Don't you- Do you remember that?
- 你認為我只是...- 別說了 別跟我說話
You think I'm- Stop!Just stop talking to me!
- 你為什麼要一直煩我?- 來吧 夥計
Why won't you just leave me alone?Come on, man.
史蒂夫 我警告你 離我遠點
[Audio Distorting] Steve, I'mtelling you, get away from me!
拜託你馬上離我遠點
Get away from me now!Please!
奇妙的的恩賜
[ Hushed Chattering ][Woman ] J Amazing grace ;
這聲音好溫柔
,V How sweet the sound J
救了我這樣的可憐人
J That saved a wretch like me ;
我曾。。。
; I once- J;
...受到上帝的仁慈與恩惠
[ Man ] ...who, by the power ofGod, are safeguarded in faith.
...雖然你現在看不見祂
Even though you do not seehim now, [Girl Crying ]
...無法形容與美麗的喜悅使你欣喜
you rejoice with an indescribableand glorious joy...
...因為你得到了信念的意願
as you attain the goalof your faith-
...和靈魂的救贖
the salvation of your soul.
你在幹什麼? 拍攝墓碑嗎?
[ Matt] What are you doing?You filming graves?
- 我不懂- 你這麼在乎幹什麼?
I don't get it.What do you care?
你都不回我電話 你為什麼不回我電?
You haven't been returning my calls.Why aren't you returning my calls?
- 我最近很忙- 你才沒有
I've been busy.No, you haven't.
你為什麼不回我電
Why aren't youreturning my calls?
我只是不想跟人聊天
I just don't feel like talking.
- 把攝影機關掉- 不
Turn off the camera.No.
安德魯 把攝影機關掉
Andrew.Andrew, turn off the camera.
安德魯 在沒有閃電紀錄的情況下...
Andrew? How did heget struck by lightning...
他是怎麼被閃電擊死的?
during a storm with norecorded lightning strikes?
怎麼會?
How?
他們還在曠野中找到史蒂夫的
And they found Steveout in the middle of a field.
史蒂夫為何在閃電暴雨中外出 安德魯?
Why would Steve go out in the middle of afield during a lightning storm, Andrew?
- 我不知道- 為什麼? 什麼?
I don't know.Why? What?
我不知道發生了什麼事 麥特
I don't knowwhat happened, Matt!
我不相信你 好嗎? 我不相信你
I don't believe you, okay?I don't believe you.
- 我要你把攝影機關掉 跟我說話- 為什麼?
I want you to turn off thecamera and talk to me. Why?
- 因為我想跟你好好聊聊- 不要命令我怎麼做 麥特
'Cause I want to have a conversation with you.Don't tell me what to do, Matt.
你不能命令我怎麼做 永遠別...
You can't tell me what to do!Don't ever tell-
- 給我...關掉它- 放開我
Give me- Shut it off!Get off of me!
安德魯 你現在在開玩笑嗎?
Andrew-Are you joking right now?
這對你來說是個遊戲嗎? 我...
Is this a joke to you? I-
你幹了什麼 安德魯?
What did you do, Andrew?
你幹了什麼?
What did you do?
我要跟誰談這件事?
Who am I supposedto tell about this?
誰? 我能跟誰談這事?
Who do I talk to?Who do I talk to about this?
你為什麼就不告訴我發生了什麼事 安德魯?
Why won't you just tell mewhat happened, Andrew?
請相信我 史蒂夫
Please believe me, Steve.
求求你 我只是...
Please, it's just I-
我不知道我做了什麼 我...
I don't know what I did. I-
我失去了控制 然後...
I lost control, and-
我很對不起
[Crying]and I'm so sorry.
這能力現在已成為我的一部分了...
This thing is just becominga part of me now,
而我不...
and I don't-
我想念你 史蒂夫
I miss you, Steve.
。。。所有步驟，我們都做得不錯，是吧？
[Coach ] ...all the drills. Good.We're all pretty good, right?
準備，上！
[Chanting ]Get ready. Go!
兄弟們？別猶豫
[ Player] You guys?Do not hesitate.
你聽說誰做了嗎？
Did you hearwho worked?
他吐得...
He was like- [ ImitatesRetching ] [ Laughing ]
哦！安德魯！
Oh! Oh, Andrew![ Imitates Retching ]
去擦乾淨！
[ Laughing ]Dry off!
完全。。。
[ Bell Rings ] [Giggling ] Totally.
喂 偉恩
Hey, Wayne!
那麼 看到這顆了嗎?
Okay, so, see this one here?
這顆我拔得很乾淨 因為我...
This one I got really clean'cause I did this little, like,
在牙根那做了個拉彈的動作 懂嗎?
lasso thing around the root,you know?
但這兩顆...
But then these two-
就沒拔得那麼好
these, I did not get as good.
有沒有看到都是斷的?
See how they're broken?
我想是因為我是從中間拔的 而不是從牙根
I think it's because I got them from themiddle, you know, instead of the root.
噢，噢
[ Bell Rings]Oh. Oh.
不俐落
Oh. Sloppy.
我在網上做了很多研究 你知道...
I've been doing a lot of reading,you know, like, online about, like-
有關進化論和適者生存之類的...
just like evolutionand, like- and natural selection...
有種東西 好嗎?
and how, like,there's this thing, right?
叫做頂級掠食者
It is called the apex predator,right?
基本上 它是整個生態系統裡最強的動物 對吧?
And basically what this is is thestrongest animal in the ecosystem, right?
做為人類嘛...
And as human beings,
我們...我們被認為是頂級掠食者...
we are- we're consideredthe apex predator,
但那只因為我們有槍和其他東西...
but only because, like, smalleranimals can't feed on us...
所以小型動物吃不了我們 對吧?
because of weaponsand stuff, right?
獅子殺死羚羊時 不會感到罪惡感 對吧?
The lion does not feel guiltywhen it kills a gazelle. Right?
就像人拍死蒼蠅時不會感到罪惡感
You do not feel guiltywhen you squash a fly.
我認為這有意義
And I thinkthat means something.
我就是覺得這有意義
[ Cracking ] I just thinkthat really means something.
這顆我拔得很乾淨 因為我...
[ On Computer] This one I got reallyclean 'cause I did this little, like,
用了套索的辦法
lasso thing.
安德魯 學校今天發生了什麼事?
[Whooshing, Thumps] Andrew,what happened at school? Huh?
- 我得去拿我媽的藥- 是嗎?
I need to go and pick up mymom's medication! Oh, yeah?
你又要不遵守規則嗎? 我們現在太強大了 安德魯
You're gonna break the rules again?We're too strong for that now, Andrew!
- 你如果要這麼做 你知道我必須怎麼做!- 你必須做什麼?
If you did that, you know what I'd have to do!You'd have to what?
- 你要想清楚- 你必須怎麼做 麥特?
You have to start thinking.What would you have to do, Matt?
你這麼做會有後果的
There are consequencesto what you do!
- 你動不了我 因為我比你強- 馬上停止這些狗屁
You could not do anything to me because Iam stronger than you. Stop that bullshit!
我知道你做了什麼 我不會再讓你那麼做的
I know what you did. I'm not gonna let you do it again!I am not going to break your stupid rules!
我不會破壞你的蠢規則 好嗎?
Okay? So just screw offand stay out of my life!
所以滾吧 別煩我的生活
[ Karen Gasping ]
我呼吸不了
I can't breathe.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 凱倫 戴特摩- 請稍等
[Andrew ] Karen Detmer.Just one moment.
藥明天才能訂
We're gonna needa next-day delivery.
價錢是$750.83.
Co-pay on that is $750.83.
- 我沒這錢
- 孩子 就像我跟你爸說的一樣...
Well, I don't have all that.Son, I told your dad, and I'll tell you.
你可以現在先付 我們明天就會訂
You can pay up front, and wecan order next-day delivery.
- 要不然我無法幫助你- 混蛋
Other than that, I can't help you.Prick.
我他媽的才不管，隨便你吧
[ Father] I don't give a shit.Do whatever you want.
噢！
[ Male Vocalist]Oh!
哦，耶
（David Bowie，專輯名Ziggy Stardus）
Ooh, yeah
傑基彈著吉他
Ziggy played guitar
同韋德和吉利配合默契
Jamming goodwith Weird and Gilly
還有來自火星的蜘蛛
And the Spiders #om Mars
他用的左手彈奏
He played it left hand
但伸的很長
But made it too far
成為一個特殊的人
Became the special man
他可以讓他們暫時停歇
Then he could leave'em to hang
他們承受重壓
They came on so loaded man
長期等待，膚色雪白
Well-hung and snow-white fan
蒼蠅在破壞我們的舞會卻不見蜘蛛的影子
So where were the spiders while the fly tried to break our balls
嘿
Hey.
喂！
Hey!
- 把你們的錢都給我- 啥? 那是誰?
Give me all your money.Uh, what? Who is that?
你別管是誰 把錢都給我 要不然...
Doesn't matter who it is.Just give me all your money or else.
要不然怎樣? 媽的
Or else? Shit, man.[ Breathing, Echoing]
媽的 夥計 那是安德魯嗎?
Shit, man. Is that Andrew?
聽起來倒像是安德魯
It sounds kind of like Andrewunder there.
你還背著安德魯那破背包
And you got Andrew'sbroke-ass backpack on.
- 你有槍嗎- 我也有一把 混帳
Oh, you got a gat?I got a gat too, bitch.
夥計
Dude!
哇哦！夥計！
Whoa, dude![ Screaming ]
快快快
Come on, come on, come on,come on, come on, come on!
快啊 快啊
Come on, come on, come on!
喂
Hey!
為了調查 攝影機必須開著
[ Man ] The camera needs tostay on for our investigation.
天啊
[ Father]Jesus Christ.
可以給我和兒子一點私人時間嗎?
Can I have a momentalone with my son?
如果他醒了 請告知外面的警官
If he regains consciousness,notify the officer outside.
好的
Yeah, yeah.
哦！
Oh![Crying Continues]
你媽死了
Your mother's dead.
我昨晚在找你時 她就死了
She died last nightwhile I was out looking for you.
我回到家 然後...
I came home, and, uh,
她躺在她的床上
she was therein her bed.
如果我當時在她身旁就好了
If I just could havebeen there for her.
你在外頭鬼混時 我總是在她身旁
I was always there for her whenyou were out screwing around.
但這一次...
And this one time-
就這一次...
this... one time...
她需要我的時候 你卻把我帶走了
that she needed me,and you took me away!
我要你對我道歉
I want youto apologize to me.
我知道你聽得到 所以我要你現在就坐起來...
I know you can hear me, so Iwant you to sit up right now...
然後對我道歉
and apologize to me.
你這自私的混帳
You selfish,selfish asshole!
這是你的錯
This is your fault!
你...
You-
你聽到了嗎?
[ Shouts ]Do you hear me?
你媽的死是你的錯
Your mother is dead,and it is your fault!
生日快樂
[ Cheering ]Happy birthday!
用力打它？用力打它？
Pound it? Pound it? [ Laughing ]
去選個禮物，去選個禮物
Go and get a present.Go and get a present. Yeah.
- 大的那個- 我的天 麥特
Yes, the big one.[Casey] Oh, my God. Matt.
麥特 你鼻子又開始了
Matt, your nose again.
你還好嗎?
Are you okay?
- 該死- 寶貝 你流了很多血
Oh, shit!Baby, you're really bleeding.
麥特 你的鼻子 天啊
[ Groaning ] Matt, your nose!Oh, my God.
你聽到了嗎? 你怎麼會聽不到?
Did you hear that?How can you not hear that?
什麼? 你聽到什麼?
Hear what? What are you hearing?It's so-
- 安德魯出事了- 凱西 快進來
Something's wrong with Andrew.[Woman ] Come in here! Casey!
打擾您的節目 我們為此抱歉 但現在...
[ Man ] We apologize for thedelay, but as of right now,
大金縣的所有新聞直升機都飛往西雅圖...- 我的天啊
every news helicopier in Greater KingCounty is headed to Seattle. Oh, my God.
我們目前得知的訊息不多...
Again, right now,we have verry little information,
但顯然在巴拉綜合醫院發生了一起爆炸事件
but if appears a bomb has gone oh'at Ballard Community Hospital
凱西 過來 過來 拜託
[ Matt] Casey, come here. Come here.Come here. Please. Please.
- 什麼? 麥特 你看到這了嗎?- 你的車鑰匙在哪?
What? No, Matt. Are you seeing this?Where are your keys at?
- 什麼? 麥特...- 留在這 我馬上回來
What? Matt- Just stay here.I'll be back.
- 我必須開過去 好嗎?- 拜託等等 麥特
I just have to drive there, okay?Please, wait! Matt, please!
- 聽著 安德魯有大麻煩了?- 安德魯什麼?
Listen, Andrew's in trouble, okay?Andrew's what?
我相信安德魯沒事的
I'm sure that Andrew is fine.[Engine Starts]
- 安德魯需要我 我得進城去- 告訴我發生了什麼事
Andrew needs me! I need to get to the city.Tell me what's going on.
該死 我必須...那是路障嗎?
Shit. I gotta get-Is that a roadblock?
沒有車往這開 告訴我怎麼回事
Nobody else is driving this way!Talk to me!
凱西 我必須思考 好嗎?
Casey, I need to think, okay?[On Bullhorn ] Stop!
我要找其他的路進城 媽的
I gotta find another way downtown.Shit!
開回去 走麥德森出口
Go back and takethe Madison exit.
快啊
[Sirens Wailing ]Come on.
- 待在這 凱西 待在這- 等等
Stay here, Casey. Stay here.Wait!
麥特 等等我
Matt, wait for me!
各單位請去巴拉德支援
[ Woman On Radio ]All units, report to BallardCommunity Hospital [ People Shouting ]
借過
Excuse me.
先生 借過
Sir, excuse me.
麥特 我們來這做什麼?
Matt!What are we doing here?
喔 我的天啊
[Crowd Gasping ][Casey] Oh, my God!
把我放下來 求求你住手
You gotta put me down!Please! Stop!
是你害我變成這樣的
[Andrew]You did this to me!
麥特 我的天啊
[ Casey ]Matt! Oh, my God!
天啊 天啊
Holy shit! Holy shit!
- 麥特- 凱西 我們得走了 現在就得走
Matt! Casey, we gotta go!We gotta go right now!
快上車 我們快走
Get in the car!Let's go.
- 安德魯不可受控了- 你在說什麼?
Andrew's out of control.What are you talking about?
我真對不起 我想告訴你的 我...
[ Crying ] I'm so sorry.I wanted to tell you. I-
我的天 麥特 停車
Oh, my God, Matt!Stop the car!
要墜了 天啊
It's gonna crash.Holy shit!
該死的
[Crashing ]Oh, shit!
- 對不起- 趕快離開道路
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.Get off the road now! [Screams]
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
抓緊我
Hold on to me!
不是我弄的 是安德魯
[ Casey Panting ]it's not me, it's Andrew!
抓緊了
Hold on![ Panting ]
我無法制止他 我無法控制車
I can't stop it! I can't control the car!I can't control it.
媽的
Shit!
安德魯 天啊 抓緊了
Andrew!Oh, God, hold on!
抓緊我
[ Casey Screaming ]Hold on to me!
我打不開門
I can't get the door open!
- 我的天- 安德魯 安德魯 住手
Oh, my God!Andrew! Andrew, stop!
- 凱西- 麥特
Casey! [ Screams ] Matt!
- 麥特
Matt![ Crashing ]
救我
Help me!
凱西 抓緊了
[ Screams ]Casey, hold on!
麥特
[ Casey Crying ]Matt.
待在這 好嗎? 你必須待在這
Stay here. Okay?You have to stay here. Okay?
麥特 求你別走 麥特
Matt, please don't go!Matt!
在針塔下有車輛著火 或許有人傷亡
[ Man On Radio ] We got a car on fireunder the Needle. Possible casualties.
馬上需要緊急應變小組
We need emergency response now
我不知怎麼形容我所目擊的
[ Man #2 On Radio ]I don't know how to describe this.
那是針塔 而如你所見的...
[ Reporter] That is the Needle we'relooking at, and as you can see, there are-
你不會相信的
[ Chattering ]You're not gonna believe this.
你看到了嗎?
Are you seeing this?
離窗戶遠點！
[ Man ]Back away from the window!
他們在幹什麼?
[ On Police Radio ]What the hell are they doing up there?
趴下
Get down![ Screaming ]
17號，注意
Seventeen, beware.[ Continues, Indistinct]
你們得馬上轉移
You Te gonna ha ve to divert
安德魯 安德魯 看著我
Andrew!Andrew, look at me!
不能再這樣下去了 好嗎? 這實在糟透了
This has to stop right now, okay?This is really, really bad!
你為什麼要接住他?
Why did you catch him?
- 聽我說 好嗎?- 我都把他扔下去了
- Listen! Just focus, okay?- I dropped him!
- 你為什麼要接住他?- 安德魯 這不是在玩遊戲
Why did you catch him?Andrew, this is not a game!
你懂嗎 你傷害了很多人
Do you understand?You're hurting people.
你太弱小了 麥特 你們全都是
You're weak, Matt! You're all weak!
- 安德魯...- 我比你們都要強大
- Andrew-- I'm stronger than all of this!
安德魯 聽我說 好嗎?我需要你聽我說話
Andrew, listen to me, okay?Just-Just- I need you to listen.
先集中精神
Just focus for a second.
不要命令我怎麼做
Do not tell me what to do!
我正試著解釋，這裡有兩個人...
[ Man On Radio ] I'm trying to explain.I go! two individuals.
- 他們阻止不了我們 我們直接離開還不算遲- 是太遲了
They can't stop us. It's not toolate for us to go. It is too late!
我受夠了 一切都結束了
I'm done! it's over!
你把我當人渣一樣對待你把我扔在一旁
You treated me like shit!You left me alone!
安德魯 你不是一個人在這啊 我和你在一起
Andrew, you're not alone up here!I'm here with you!
我應該一直守在你旁邊的 但我現在在這啊
I should have been with you all along!But I'm here now!
我們可以停止這一切 就你和我
And we can stop this right now,you and me!
安德魯 我們可以直接飛走 遠離這裡
Andrew, we can just fly away.We can get out of here.
我們可以當家人
We can be family.
安德魯 安德魯 看看你自己
Andrew.Andrew, look at yourself.
- 這不是你啊- 我是頂級掠食者
This isn't who you are.[Whispers] I'm an apex predator.
什麼?
What?
我是頂級掠食者
I'm an apex predator.
不 不
No! No!
噢，天啊，叫員警！
[Woman ] Oh, my gosh!Call the police!
安德魯 不
Andrew, no![Crowd Screams]
噢，哇哦！
[Siren Wailing]Oh! Whoa!
- 保羅 離窗戶遠一點- 好的 好的
[Woman] Paul! Paul, stay awayfrom the window! Okay, okay!
- 保羅 別站在窗戶旁- 你看到了嗎?
Paul! Don't stand at the window!Are you seeing this? Hey!
趴下 親愛的
Stay down, babe! Stay down!
安德魯
Andrew!
兩人落地 一人受傷
[ Man On Police Radio] Two subjects down.One injured, one mobile.
安德魯? 安德魯 看著我
[Woman Screaming ]Andrew? Andrew, look at me.
沒事的 你不會有事的 好嗎?
This is all gonna be fine.You're gonna be all right, okay?
我會找人救你 好嗎?
I'm gonna get you help, okay?
各單位注意，丹尼街發生4級事件，速支援
[ Woman On Police Radio]All units, respond Code 4 to Denny Way
快走 這裡不安全
[ Grunts ]Get out of here! it's not safe!
安德魯? 安德魯?
Andrew? Andrew?
你還不明白嗎？不准動！
[ Man ] Are you getting this?Don't move!
別開槍 別開槍
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
等一下 等等 等等 我需要救援 我需要救援
Hold on! Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!I need help! I need help!
他看起來像是被人拿槍指著，但是。。。
[ Man On Radio ] He appearsto be held at gunpoint but-
噢上帝啊！
Oh, my God!
手舉起來！請別開槍！
[ Officer] Arms up in the air![ Matt] Don't shoot, please!
他受傷了
He's hurt!
- 趴在地上- 等等 等等
Get on the ground!Wait! Wait!
- 照他說的坐- 馬上趴下
Do what he says!Now, get down!
- 不准起來- 趴在地上
- Do not get up!- Get on the ground!
請別開槍！我們會開槍的！
[ Matt ] Please don't shoot!We will shoot you!
- 我什麼都不會做- 小心玻璃
- I'm not gonna do anything!- Whoa, whoa, whoa! The glass!
開他一槍！
[ Siren Approaching ]Take him out!
別來煩我
Leave me alone!
靠！
Shit!
哇哦！哇哦！ 喔喔！
Whoa! Whoa! Wow!
我們看到發生多起爆炸
We have multiple explosions.
- 趕快就位- 我們看到他們了
Get in position!We have 'em in our sights!
已就位！原地待命！
We're covered!Hold it right there! [Gun Cocks]
不！住手！
No! Stop!
我們已經把你包圍了
We have you surrounded!
- 不- 手舉高讓我們看見
No!Hands where we can see 'em!
趴下 趴下
Stay down! Stay down!
趴下！重覆，不准動！
Stay down!I repeat, do not move!
其他單位在遠處那邊！
Additional units on the far side!
趴下！
Yo, stay down!
趴下 不許動
Stay down! Don't move!
安德魯！安德魯！
Andrew! Andrew!
住手！別傷害他們！安德魯！
Stop! Don't hurt them!Andrew!
開火！
Open fire!
安德魯!
Andrew!
安德魯 快住手
Andrew! Andrew, stop!
求求你 住手
Please, stop!
安德魯！
Andrew!
別逼我這麼做
Don't make me do this!
住手
Stop!
彙報傷亡情況
[ Man On Radio ]...reports of casualties.
至少擊毀兩個物體
At least two structureshave been destroyed
我認為他們都倒下了！
[Siren Wailing] [ Man ] Ithink they're both down!
死亡兩人
[ Man On Radio ]Two men out
顯示給我看東面情況。。。
Show me right now eastbound on-
是，長官我在兩街區外，我看到了
Yes, sir.I'm about two blocks away. I see it.
行動
Move up.
喂 你在幹什麼?
Hey! Oh!What are you doing?
嘿 安德魯
Hey, Andrew.
我只是想說...
I just wanted to say that...
我很抱歉 還有..
I'm sorry and, uh,
我...我希望...
I- I hope...
你懂我做了我必須做的事
that you know that I didwhat I had to do.
你並不是個壞人 這我知道
You're not a bad person.I know that.
這是唯一重要的
That's all that matters.
還有 我要告訴你...
And, uh, I want you to know...
我從今以後會變更好的
that I'm gonna be betterfrom now on.
我會幫助人們
I'm gonna help people.
我要查明我們在那洞裡發生了什麼事
[ Exhales] I'm gonna find outwhat happened to us down there.
我不在乎需要多少時間
I don't care how long it takes.
我要找到答案
I'm gonna get answers.
為了你和史蒂夫 我會找到的
I'm gonna do it for you,and I'm gonna do it for Steve.
還有...
And...
我...
I just-
我愛你 夥計
I love you, man.
我到最後都沒有機會告訴你...
[ Sighs ] I didn't everget a chance to tell you,
我愛你
but I love you.
還有
And guess what.
你做到了
You made it.
喔喔！
Whoo-hoo!
[ Echoing ]Whoo-hoo!
多美啊
Isn't it beautiful?
再見了 安德魯
Good-bye, Andrew.